<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hosting of the IATI Registry</title>
    <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/hosting-of-the-iati-registry/1205</link>
    <description>We are pleased to announce that we have secured a new hosting arrangement for the Registry.

Over the past three months we have undertaken a review of CKAN developers and selected [Derilinx](https://derilinx.com/) to take over from [Viderum](https://www.viderum.com/), our current host.

[Derilinx](https://derilinx.com/solutions/ckan/) is a leading provider of CKAN development and hosting, including the maintenance of the Irish Open Data Portal [data.gov.ie](https://data.gov.ie/) on behalf of the Department of Public Expenditure and Reform, and the development of Dublin City Council’s Open Data Portal [data.dublinked.ie.](https://data.dublinked.ie/) Deirdre Lee, Derilinx CEO, is co-chair of the [W3C Data on the Web Best Practices Working Group](https://www.w3.org/TR/dwbp/) and contributes to a number of European Commission Joinup Working Groups.

Preparation for the migration will take place over the next two months and will be completed by 30th March at the latest when our current contract with Viderum will expire. We will keep the community posted on progress. At the point of migration all current functionality will be transferred and there should be no change or disruption to publishing processes.

Special thanks to @dalepotter for his painstaking work in making this happen.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 11:03:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Notifications</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/hosting-of-the-iati-registry/1205.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hosting of the IATI Registry</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[bill_anderson]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>We are pleased to announce that we have secured a new hosting arrangement for the Registry.</p>
<p>Over the past three months we have undertaken a review of CKAN developers and selected <a href="https://derilinx.com/">Derilinx</a> to take over from <a href="https://www.viderum.com/">Viderum</a>, our current host.</p>
<p><a href="https://derilinx.com/solutions/ckan/">Derilinx</a> is a leading provider of CKAN development and hosting, including the maintenance of the Irish Open Data Portal <a href="https://data.gov.ie/">data.gov.ie</a> on behalf of the Department of Public Expenditure and Reform, and the development of Dublin City Council’s Open Data Portal <a href="https://data.dublinked.ie/">data.dublinked.ie.</a> Deirdre Lee, Derilinx CEO, is co-chair of the <a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/dwbp/">W3C Data on the Web Best Practices Working Group</a> and contributes to a number of European Commission Joinup Working Groups.</p>
<p>Preparation for the migration will take place over the next two months and will be completed by 30th March at the latest when our current contract with Viderum will expire. We will keep the community posted on progress. At the point of migration all current functionality will be transferred and there should be no change or disruption to publishing processes.</p>
<p>Special thanks to <a class="mention" href="/u/dalepotter">@dalepotter</a> for his painstaking work in making this happen.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/hosting-of-the-iati-registry/1205/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/hosting-of-the-iati-registry/1205/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 11:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-1205-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/hosting-of-the-iati-registry/1205.rss">Hosting of the IATI Registry</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
