<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>IATI Humanitarian next steps</title>
    <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-humanitarian-next-steps/95</link>
    <description>@bill_anderson wrote this in the OKFest topic (as a &quot;new user&quot;, I&#39;m not allowed to post any more replies there):

&lt;blockquote&gt;
Great context

So what to do?

1. Get a humanitarian marker in place
2. Bring FTS extension covering emergencies, appeals, etc, into the main standard
3. Redefine timeliness for humanitarian needs: best practice is daily, not monthly
4. Focus on Result Outputs: Get WFP in the saddle for this
5. Get into a situation asap that EDRIS and FTS feel comfortable with importing IATI data  
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

Thanks, Bill — I that&#39;s an excellent start.  First, I&#39;d like to add a couple more points for discussion:

* Consider making _transaction_ optional for field-level humanitarian reporting (an NGO will know outputs, e.g. how many anti-Malarial kits were distributed, but might not know how much money those represent until later).
* Figure out the role of the cluster system in humanitarian field-level reporting. Since clusters already collect 3W information from their partners, are they the sweet spot for getting IATI humanitarian field-level information, or do we want to invest more energy reaching out downstream to the individual implementing NGOs and agencies?
* Work with Publish What You Fund to come up with different report-card criteria for different types of humanitarian reporting.

For your original points, I think daily reporting could make sense from some HQ-level information systems, but the most-frequent I&#39;ve seen so far at the field cluster level is weekly, and that&#39;s only for an L3 (highest level) emergency that&#39;s developing fast.  Monthly, quarterly, or semi-annually seems more common for 3W, depending on the crisis and how fast it changes. </description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 07:06:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Humanitarian</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-humanitarian-next-steps/95.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>IATI Humanitarian next steps</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[bill_anderson]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Cheers David,</p>
<p>My mind was very much on the top down reporting when I wrote those points, and I appreciate that is a small part of the bigger picture. Personally I have no experience of humanitarian field operations and we are going to need proper guidance from you to get this right.</p>
<p>On the top down I was particularly concerned about whether IATI can be an efficient channel for pledges and commitments in the early days of an emergency. This would require daily reporting (and a new transaction type for pledges)</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-humanitarian-next-steps/95/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-humanitarian-next-steps/95/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 07:06:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-95-2</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-humanitarian-next-steps/95.rss">IATI Humanitarian next steps</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>IATI Humanitarian next steps</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[David_Megginson]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="/u/bill_anderson">@bill_anderson</a> wrote this in the OKFest topic (as a “new user”, I’m not allowed to post any more replies there):</p>
<blockquote>
Great context
<p>So what to do?</p>
<ol>
<li>Get a humanitarian marker in place</li>
<li>Bring FTS extension covering emergencies, appeals, etc, into the main standard</li>
<li>Redefine timeliness for humanitarian needs: best practice is daily, not monthly</li>
<li>Focus on Result Outputs: Get WFP in the saddle for this</li>
<li>Get into a situation asap that EDRIS and FTS feel comfortable with importing IATI data</li>
</ol>
</blockquote>
<p>Thanks, Bill — I that’s an excellent start.  First, I’d like to add a couple more points for discussion:</p>
<ul>
<li>Consider making <em>transaction</em> optional for field-level humanitarian reporting (an NGO will know outputs, e.g. how many anti-Malarial kits were distributed, but might not know how much money those represent until later).</li>
<li>Figure out the role of the cluster system in humanitarian field-level reporting. Since clusters already collect 3W information from their partners, are they the sweet spot for getting IATI humanitarian field-level information, or do we want to invest more energy reaching out downstream to the individual implementing NGOs and agencies?</li>
<li>Work with Publish What You Fund to come up with different report-card criteria for different types of humanitarian reporting.</li>
</ul>
<p>For your original points, I think daily reporting could make sense from some HQ-level information systems, but the most-frequent I’ve seen so far at the field cluster level is weekly, and that’s only for an L3 (highest level) emergency that’s developing fast.  Monthly, quarterly, or semi-annually seems more common for 3W, depending on the crisis and how fast it changes.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-humanitarian-next-steps/95/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-humanitarian-next-steps/95/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 15:38:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-95-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-humanitarian-next-steps/95.rss">IATI Humanitarian next steps</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
