<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>TAG Piccolo!, a miniTAG in Rome October 6</title>
    <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/tag-piccolo-a-minitag-in-rome-october-6/994</link>
    <description>FAO and Open Ag are jointly hosting a &quot;TAG Piccolo,&quot; aka miniTAG, at FAO HQ in Rome the day after Members&#39; Assembly, Oct 6. The official announcement is below.

What we&#39;d like to know now is:

* Will you be joining us? If so, please register here: https://www.eventbrite.com/e/minitag-rome-tickets-36999462388
* What would you like to talk about? If you have a proposal for a session, a discussion, or even a theme, please submit it here: https://goo.gl/forms/mB4e6PLmKXISC1F53

See you in Rome!

&gt;The Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO) and the Initiative for Open Ag Funding invite you to join IATI&#39;s Technical Advisory Group community at a TAG Piccolo (i.e. a miniTAG) at FAO&#39;s HQ in Rome on Friday 6 October. You do not have to be an IATI member or have attended the Members&#39; Assembly to join and everyone is welcome (though space is limited).

&gt; The theme will be based on submitted proposals, but will likely include:
&gt; •	A presentation and feedback workshop on an FAO-led proposal to update OECD DAC classifications
&gt; •	Demonstrations of IATI publishing and data use tools by the Open Ag initiative
&gt; •	Discussion of the role of secondary publishers in IATI

&gt; To register for the meeting or for more information contact Reid Porter: rporter@interaction.org</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 20:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Events</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/tag-piccolo-a-minitag-in-rome-october-6/994.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>TAG Piccolo!, a miniTAG in Rome October 6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[reidmporter]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>FAO and Open Ag are jointly hosting a “TAG Piccolo,” aka miniTAG, at FAO HQ in Rome the day after Members’ Assembly, Oct 6. The official announcement is below.</p>
<p>What we’d like to know now is:</p>
<ul>
<li>Will you be joining us? If so, please register here: <a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/minitag-rome-tickets-36999462388" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.eventbrite.com/e/minitag-rome-tickets-36999462388</a>
</li>
<li>What would you like to talk about? If you have a proposal for a session, a discussion, or even a theme, please submit it here: <a href="https://goo.gl/forms/mB4e6PLmKXISC1F53" rel="nofollow noopener">https://goo.gl/forms/mB4e6PLmKXISC1F53</a>
</li>
</ul>
<p>See you in Rome!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO) and the Initiative for Open Ag Funding invite you to join IATI’s Technical Advisory Group community at a TAG Piccolo (i.e. a miniTAG) at FAO’s HQ in Rome on Friday 6 October. You do not have to be an IATI member or have attended the Members’ Assembly to join and everyone is welcome (though space is limited).</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>The theme will be based on submitted proposals, but will likely include:<br>
•	A presentation and feedback workshop on an FAO-led proposal to update OECD DAC classifications<br>
•	Demonstrations of IATI publishing and data use tools by the Open Ag initiative<br>
•	Discussion of the role of secondary publishers in IATI</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>To register for the meeting or for more information contact Reid Porter: <a href="mailto:rporter@interaction.org">rporter@interaction.org</a></p>
</blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/tag-piccolo-a-minitag-in-rome-october-6/994/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/tag-piccolo-a-minitag-in-rome-october-6/994/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 20:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-994-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/tag-piccolo-a-minitag-in-rome-october-6/994.rss">TAG Piccolo!, a miniTAG in Rome October 6</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
