<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>IATI Community Discussions - Latest posts</title>
    <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org</link>
    <description>Latest posts</description>
      <item>
        <title>Discuss is going into read-only mode</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@IATI-techteam IATI Technical Team]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Dear Discuss-community,</p>
<p>As you know we will be migrating this platform, both content and users, to the new IATI Connect platform. As of  <strong>Wednesday 25 of November - 12pm (GMT/UTC)  IATI Discuss will be in read-only mode</strong>. This allows us to move all content over for the launch on the 30th.</p>
<p>The new IATI Connect will have:</p>
<ul>
<li>A dedicated space for the Discuss-Archive (containing our current Discuss and a link to existing archive);</li>
<li>Ongoing / specific discussions will be integrated into the new IATI Communities, and would hopefully provide an opportunity to widen the audience and embed it into the wider IATI discussions;</li>
<li>IATI-wide consultations and technical discussions, such as the Standard Management category, will be housed under the IATI Connect Consultations;</li>
</ul>
<p>What does this mean for you in practice?</p>
<ul>
<li>Every migration takes some time. Therefore, as of Wednesday 25th of November - 12pm (GMT/UTC) the Discuss-content and users will be ‘on the move’. Any changes made on Discuss post 12pm (should be disabled) and will definitely not be moved across to the new platform.</li>
<li>You will all receive a notification (by email) once we have arrived at our new location: IATI Connect. Through that notification you will be assigned a new profile on the platform (which is pre-arranged) and additional relevant onboarding information.</li>
<li>IATI Discuss will stay in read-only mode for 6 months before being removed. This will allow us time to make sure no content is lost and is findable on the new platform.</li>
</ul>
<p>Once you access your profile, you’ll be able to join a Community of Practice, register for events, contribute to discussions, see other content specific to those groups, and much more.</p>
<p>Of course we hope everything will go smoothly, but every migration is exciting. In case you have any questions or comments please send us an email through <a href="mailto:connect@iatistandard.org">connect@iatistandard.org</a>.</p>
<p>Thank you for your understanding, and we look forward to seeing you ‘on the other side’.</p>
<p>Best,</p>
<p>IATI Secretariat</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/discuss-is-going-into-read-only-mode/2054/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 17:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6590</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Share views and join user-testing for IATI’s new community platform (November 12th)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@IATI-techteam IATI Technical Team]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Dear Discuss-community,</p>
<p>As you know we will be migrating this platform, both content and users, to the new IATI Connect platform. As of  <strong>Wednesday 25 of November - 12pm (GMT/UTC)  IATI Discuss will be in read-only mode</strong>. This allows us to move all content over for the launch on the 30th.</p>
<p>The new IATI Connect will have:</p>
<ul>
<li>A dedicated space for the Discuss-Archive (containing our current Discuss and a link to existing archive);</li>
<li>Ongoing / specific discussions will be integrated into the new IATI Communities, and would hopefully provide an opportunity to widen the audience and embed it into the wider IATI discussions;</li>
<li>IATI-wide consultations and technical discussions, such as the Standard Management category, will be housed under the IATI Connect Consultations;</li>
</ul>
<p>What does this mean for you in practice?</p>
<ul>
<li>Every migration takes some time. Therefore, as of Wednesday 25th of November - 12pm (GMT/UTC) the Discuss-content and users will be ‘on the move’. Any changes made on Discuss post 12pm (should be disabled) and will definitely not be moved across to the new platform.</li>
<li>You will all receive a notification (by email) once we have arrived at our new location: IATI Connect. Through that notification you will be assigned a new profile on the platform (which is pre-arranged) and additional relevant onboarding information.</li>
</ul>
<p>Once you access your profile, you’ll be able to join a Community of Practice, register for events, contribute to discussions, see other content specific to those groups, and much more.</p>
<p>Of course we hope everything will go smoothly, but every migration is exciting. In case you have any questions or comments please send us an email through <a href="mailto:connect@iatistandard.org">connect@iatistandard.org</a>.</p>
<p>Thank you for your understanding, and we look forward to seeing you ‘on the other side’.</p>
<p>Best,</p>
<p>IATI Secretariat</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/share-views-and-join-user-testing-for-iati-s-new-community-platform-november-12th/2037/8</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 17:06:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6589</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Launch IATI Connect and COPs (Monday November 30th)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@sanderhees Sander Hees]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Dear Discuss-community,</p>
<p>As you know, on Monday November 30th we will be launching IATI’s first Communities of Practice and IATI Connect-platform (which will also provide space for the Discuss-archive and active threads).</p>
<p>Are you ready to Connect? We have 125 registered participants for the launch-event, but registration is still open! Check out our latest animation announcing the COP-launch and how you can register:</p>
<div class="onebox lazyYT lazyYT-container" data-youtube-id="I661FrMxmLE" data-youtube-title="IATI Communities of Practice launch (with subtitles)" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque">
  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I661FrMxmLE" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">
    <img class="ytp-thumbnail-image" src="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/I661FrMxmLE/maxresdefault.jpg" title="IATI Communities of Practice launch (with subtitles)" width="690" height="388">
  </a>
</div>
 ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/launch-iati-connect-and-cops-monday-november-30th/2051/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 06:42:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6586</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Using near real-time IATI data to track aid flows</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@bill_anderson Bill Anderson]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p><strong>Webinar: Using near real-time IATI data to track aid flows during the Covid-19 crisis</strong></p>
<p><strong>Date: 30th November 2020</strong></p>
<p><strong>Time: 12 noon-1pm GMT</strong></p>
<p><strong>Hosted by: Development Initiatives</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://zoom.us/meeting/register/tJYoc-mvrTwtE9I36cFB2b2sa_v9WsLGpgbc"><strong>Register here</strong></a></p>
<p><strong>Moderator: Carolyn Culey, Director of Engagement and Partnerships</strong></p>
<p><strong>Speakers:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Global analysis – Amy Dodd, Head of Engagement</strong></li>
<li><strong>East Africa analysis – Martha Bekele, Senior Analyst</strong></li>
<li><strong>Methodology – Bill Anderson, Information Architect</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>During the current Covid-19 crisis, having data on aid spending in as near to real-time as possible, has never been more important in understanding current trends and informing decisions. Detailed information on ODA spending in 2020 will not be published by the OECD DAC until the end of 2021. DI’s analysis uses near real-time IATI data to show <a href="https://devinit.org/resources/how-aid-changing-covid-19-pandemic/">how aid is changing during the Covid-19 pandemic</a>, and examines the implications of this. While our initial report focusses on global trends, a forthcoming report by our analysts’ team in East Africa looks at country-level data in Kenya, Uganda, Tanzania, and Rwanda.</p>
<p><strong>DI will present key findings from both reports, followed by a Q&amp;A session on these.</strong></p>
<p>Using IATI data in this way has presented both opportunities and challenges. In the second part of this webinar, DI will explain the methodology behind our analysis and highlight some of the issues we have encountered in using real-time IATI data. These are being logged and shared with IATI’s business analysts, to provide a feedback loop to publishers so they can further improve the quality of their data, to make it more usable for analysts.</p>
<p><strong>There will be a further round of Q&amp;A on methodology and on data challenges.</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://zoom.us/meeting/register/tJYoc-mvrTwtE9I36cFB2b2sa_v9WsLGpgbc"><strong>Register here</strong></a></p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/using-near-real-time-iati-data-to-track-aid-flows/2050/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 15:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6585</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reverso validator?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@matmaxgeds Matt Geddes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Thanks…the ability to swap between ‘see results by ruleset’ and ‘by activity’ feature is very helpful e.g. if I have a publisher for whom we are having difficulty parsing their data for a specific element, then this is much easier that going through each activity one-by one (as I think is the option in the new validator?)</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/reverso-validator/2033/6</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 08:19:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6583</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reverso validator?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@stevieflow Steven Flower]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>We have <em>something like this</em> in our <a href="https://iati.cove.opendataservices.coop/" rel="nofollow noopener">IATI CoVE tool</a></p>
<p>Specifically, we added this on the ruleset tests, so you can group the feedback by activity or by ruleset.  Is that what you meant <a class="mention" href="/u/matmaxgeds">@matmaxgeds</a> ?</p>
<p><a href="https://iati.cove.opendataservices.coop/data/849c8126-d9e4-430e-9d5b-958caa26b08e" rel="nofollow noopener">Here’s an example</a> on the first dataset listed as invalid on the IATI dashboard</p>
<p>Added bonus: you can then convert that IATI XML into a spreadsheet - whereby the one-to-many aspect of IATI is pushed into relevant sheets.  I find this super useful!</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/reverso-validator/2033/5</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 21:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6581</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reverso validator?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@matmaxgeds Matt Geddes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Thanks <a class="mention" href="/u/iati-techteam">@IATI-techteam</a> - as a non publisher, but with a data use hat on, I am trying to figure out how the Validator could be made useful e.g. “what is the most common error in element X”, or what errors have gone longest without being fixed etc.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/reverso-validator/2033/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 18:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6580</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reverso validator?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@IATI-techteam IATI Technical Team]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Thanks <a class="mention" href="/u/matmaxgeds">@matmaxgeds</a>. Apologies for very slow response on this!</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>As you know, the validator validates single files. For each file  you can see the errors presented as you suggest, but currently not a summary for all files.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>To your point on being able to see a list of all errors, we are actually now working on developing a feature to be added to the validator that gives you a summary of <em>critical</em>, <em>errors</em> and <em>warnings</em> <strong>per publisher</strong> to support measures in the IATI Results Framework.  This will not yet include the detailed summary for specific error types that you suggest. I agree it is indeed something that will be useful to have in the future, and that we can look into, but we are now prioritising the measure for the results framework.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>On the public API, currently there is no public API for the validator.  With the launch of the validator, we have been engaging with publishers directly and are now starting to consult on user requirements for a public API.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Hope this helps but happy to speak if more helpful.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/reverso-validator/2033/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 11:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6578</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reverso validator?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@matmaxgeds Matt Geddes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>+1 month bump <a class="mention" href="/u/iati-techteam">@IATI-techteam</a> any ideas? It would be useful to see where the majority of errors were to know which parts of the standard needed most work?</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/reverso-validator/2033/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 20:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6575</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>UX Research for IATI- deadline 20 November</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@IATI-techteam IATI Technical Team]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p><strong>IATI are seeking a UX Researcher to understand more about IATI publishers and the functionality they require as they publish to IATI.</strong></p>
<p>The IATI Governing Board has asked the Secretariat to conduct an options analysis to assess potential approaches to a publishing tool. While we have already learned a great deal about our diverse community of more than 1,200 publishers of different types and sizes, we need to understand more about our publishers and the functionality they require as they publish to IATI. This will enable us to analyse options for a publishing tool based on publisher input. All sizes of publishing organisations should be consulted as part of this exercise.</p>
<p>For more information, please see the <a href="https://devinit.org/work-for-us/vacancies/independent-consultant-ux-researcher-iati/">specific requirements and deliverables on this page</a>. Please share with your networks!</p>
<p><strong>Closing date:</strong> 20 November 2020</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/ux-research-for-iati-deadline-20-november/2044/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 10:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6574</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>[Rejected] New Organisation Identifier: XI-IATI-LFTW</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@stevieflow Steven Flower]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="rolfkleef" data-post="3" data-topic="2040">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/user_avatar/discuss.iatistandard.org/rolfkleef/40/82_2.png" class="avatar"> rolfkleef:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I don’t know if IATI still has an arrangement</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>As stated, there isn’t any.  Currently, org-id <em>still</em> sits with us at Open Data Services Cooperative, having started life as a cross-standards collaboration.  We still maintain things , and have arrangements to respond to requests from initiatives such as Open Contracting, 360Giving &amp; Beneficial Ownership Data Standard.  From our perspective, this is infrastructure that helps us all.</p>
<p>We’ve reached out to the <a class="mention" href="/u/iati-techteam">@IATI-techteam</a> in that we do have some technical things in place that make it easier to submit a proposal (directly as a Pull Request), which we hope is helpful.</p>
<p>BUT - the core issue here is about research, not code.  It’s still amazing that for an international initiative, we’re asking people to go and research lists in other languages and countries.  We’re very clear that this is research we are not qualified to do, or even want to do it!  I think we need to have this conversation in IATI very quickly.</p>
<p>To avoid a long thread on the title of XI-IATI-LFTW, I’ll create a new post here on Discuss.  Look forward to the XI-engagement…</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/rejected-new-organisation-identifier-xi-iati-lftw/2040/8</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 18:09:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6573</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Share views and join user-testing for IATI’s new community platform (November 12th)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@siemvaessen Siem Vaessen]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Thanks <a class="mention" href="/u/aparr">@aparr</a> for the explainer.</p>
<p>As I -and many other I believe- was unaware of how this came to life. Your outline clearly clarifies the procedures. Thanks for this.</p>
<p>And hope everyone is breathing again in the US after the election week… <img src="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/images/emoji/twitter/sun_behind_small_cloud.png?v=9" title=":sun_behind_small_cloud:" class="emoji" alt=":sun_behind_small_cloud:"></p>
<p>Looking forward to the new community platform.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/share-views-and-join-user-testing-for-iati-s-new-community-platform-november-12th/2037/7</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 15:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6571</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>[Approved] New Organisation Identifier: XI-IATI-SDPI</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@IATI-techteam IATI Technical Team]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>There has been no objection to this code and it will be approved.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/approved-new-organisation-identifier-xi-iati-sdpi/2039/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 09:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6570</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>[Rejected] New Organisation Identifier: XI-IATI-LFTW</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@IATI-techteam IATI Technical Team]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Hi <a class="mention" href="/u/rolfkleef">@rolfkleef</a> and <a class="mention" href="/u/michelle_iom">@Michelle_IOM</a> ! Apologies for the slow response!</p>
<p>As <a class="mention" href="/u/rolfkleef">@rolfkleef</a> has identified as of 6th of April 2020, ORG-ID guide will not be adding new, unsolicited entries. IATI doesn’t have a specific arrangement.</p>
<p>Similar to <a href="https://github.com/org-id/register/issues/401">this request</a>, unless there is fully <a href="http://docs.org-id.guide/en/latest/contribute/#proposing-a-new-entry">prepared proposal</a>, the addition won’t be made to org-id.guide.</p>
<p>Looking at the <a href="https://www.bmi.gv.at/">BMI - Bundesministerium</a> site,  and thanks to your input, we were able to identify the Light for the World International and create a <a href="https://github.com/org-id/register/issues/429">Github proposal</a>.</p>
<p>As such, I’ll put this proposal as rejected and wait to hear from org-id.guide on the timeline for getting this reviewed and added to org-id.guide.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/rejected-new-organisation-identifier-xi-iati-lftw/2040/6</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 11:23:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6568</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Share views and join user-testing for IATI’s new community platform (November 12th)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@aparr Annelise Parr]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Hi All</p>
<p>Coming in here with the background for this work and to try to bring back the positive mood! For sure we need some positivity as it’s election day today here in the US, and we’re all holding our collective breath…</p>
<p>The Board was presented with the idea of an IATI Community platform to facilitate the establishment of the planned Communities of Practices (and help support collaboration for Working Groups) in their November 2019 meeting and approved the approach at that time, as published in its minutes Rory has mentioned.</p>
<p>Budget was allocated to this activity and included in the 2020 work plan, and approved by the Governing Board as an important feature to support the new Working Groups and COPs. With UNDP leading on Community work, the Board was also made aware that UNDP would use its established Long Term Agreement (LTA) for community engagement platforms as a procurement approach at this time, to maximize cost efficiency and to ensure the project could be delivered within the necessary time frame. The procurement process through LTA is itself a rigorous two-step competitive process in which specific projects are sent out to all LTA holders for bids, which are then evaluated on a cost/value basis.</p>
<p>This project followed these UNDP procurement guidelines; the Terms of Reference for the project were reviewed by the Governing Board and circulated for bids to all UNDP LTA holders. The Board has been updated on progress during each quarterly meeting.</p>
<p>I really do want to emphasise the great progress here - the team has been working incredibly hard on both policy and tools to get COPs and WGs up and running so that we can really engage well as a community across a range of different subjects. It’s especially important during these times when we can’t have face to face meetings.</p>
<p>Please do get involved in the user testing and stay in touch with us with any feedback!</p>
<p>All the best, Annelise</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/share-views-and-join-user-testing-for-iati-s-new-community-platform-november-12th/2037/6</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 19:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6567</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>[Rejected] New Organisation Identifier: XI-IATI-LFTW</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rolfkleef Rolf Kleef]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I think the main issue is that org-id decides whether AT-ZVR will be used as prefix. Since ZVR is the abbreviation used by the Ministry as well, that is likely. But not guaranteed.</p>
<p>It looks like a pretty straightforward process to add, but I don’t know about the arrangements, or the research that org-id wants to do or the information they would need.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/rejected-new-organisation-identifier-xi-iati-lftw/2040/5</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 10:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6566</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>[Rejected] New Organisation Identifier: XI-IATI-LFTW</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Michelle_IOM Michelle Levesque]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Dear Rolf,</p>
<p>Ok so I understand the ministry won’t be added to the org-id repository.  But why does the ministry have to be in the org-id repository in order for the org to use the ministry generated ID?  I still don’t understand why they need an IATI issued ID if one exists in the public domain.  And it seems you too don’t understand.  Hoping the tech team can jump in here.  Seems you’ve already provided the ID here.</p>
<p>Kind Regards,<br>
Michelle</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/rejected-new-organisation-identifier-xi-iati-lftw/2040/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 10:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6565</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>[Rejected] New Organisation Identifier: XI-IATI-LFTW</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rolfkleef Rolf Kleef]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>There is no ticket to add the Ministry to the org-id repository, and according to the repository:</p>
<blockquote>
<h2>Current status (as of 6th April 2020)</h2>
<p>We (Open Data Services Co-operative) are not currently adding new, unsolicited entries to org-id while we focus our efforts on improving the service. (Those improvements will take longer than initially planned because of the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic.) Some open data standards have made arrangements to add fully-researched org-id entries. Requests from those organisations will be dealt with under those arrangements.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I don’t know if IATI still has an arrangement, to me it would also make more sense to <a href="https://www.bmi.gv.at/609/zvr.aspx" rel="nofollow noopener">get the Ministry into org-id</a> and let them have AT-ZVR-315688676 as their IATI identfiier.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/rejected-new-organisation-identifier-xi-iati-lftw/2040/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 10:17:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6564</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Share views and join user-testing for IATI’s new community platform (November 12th)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@siemvaessen Siem Vaessen]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Hi <a class="mention" href="/u/sanderhees">@sanderhees</a> and welcome to IATI <img src="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> and discuss.</p>
<p>I’d be happy to chip in. Am I correct in understanding a platform(?) of sorts has been developed by now and is to be launched end of year!? If so under what conditions and specifications has this been developed and what is the foundation (functional requirements etc.) for this ‘platform’? At what costs has this been developed? Has this been developed in the IATI spirit of open-source code (as with all other IATI software tools around) or not? I was unable to find any codebase for a new community platform on <a href="https://github.com/IATI" rel="nofollow noopener">https://github.com/IATI</a>.</p>
<p>In light of <a class="mention" href="/u/rory_scott">@rory_scott</a>’s request  I’d also be interested to learn <strong>who</strong> developed that new (community) platform and also eager to learn <strong>how</strong> this went out to procurement? Was the community notified of some tender (ToR) for this work? IATI does publish tenders well below the $80,000 marker.</p>
<p>Very interested to learn what this platform entails but as interested how this work came to life in the first place.</p>
<p>In the light of transparency accountability (IATI…) this is now pretty vague~ish and should be explained in most transparent way possible to the community it serves and its members imho.</p>
<p>I don’t mean to be break the positive mood, but this process is now extremely unclear.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/share-views-and-join-user-testing-for-iati-s-new-community-platform-november-12th/2037/5</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 15:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6562</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Share views and join user-testing for IATI’s new community platform (November 12th)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@sanderhees Sander Hees]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Hi <a class="mention" href="/u/rory_scott">@rory_scott</a>, thank you!! And it’s great to hear you’ll be joining November 12th. I’ll share the invite and some additional information via e-mail shortly.</p>
<p>In short: as you mentioned already, in 2019, IATI members approved the Strategic Plan (2020-2025) that lists the strengthening of the IATI community, as well as the initiation of a combination “Working Groups” and “Communities of Practice” model to promote knowledge-sharing and peer-learning around the publishing and use of IATI data, as key priorities. What this means in practice is that IATI would like to build on its existing, but relatively decentralised, community of practitioners (currently more than 400 people in its Discuss platform) to establish a stronger knowledge-sharing infrastructure and technical tools to facilitate access to guidance products, promote interactive online learning opportunities, and support collaboration to strengthen the impact and quality of IATI data worldwide.</p>
<p>Hope this clarifies a bit, expect my Outlook invite for November 12th shortly.</p>
<p>Best,</p>
<p>Sander</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/share-views-and-join-user-testing-for-iati-s-new-community-platform-november-12th/2037/4</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 05:54:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6561</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Share views and join user-testing for IATI’s new community platform (November 12th)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rory_scott Rory Scott]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Hi <a class="mention" href="/u/sanderhees">@sanderhees</a>, welcome to the community and to discuss <img src="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>I will be joining!</p>
<p>In the meantime, could I ask where I might be able to find the original terms of reference, user stories, and any other relevant materials for this project? There’s no mention of it in the <a href="https://iatistandard.org/en/governance/iati-strategic-plan-2020-2025/" rel="nofollow noopener">strategic plan</a>, and although I see some mention in the <a href="https://iatistandard.org/en/governance/governing-board-meeting-minutes/" rel="nofollow noopener">board minutes</a> from November 2019 onward, there is no more detail than a record of it’s proposal and an initial budget of $80,000.</p>
<p>Looking forward to seeing what’s been built, but just want to know what the aims and expectations should be!</p>
<p>Thank you!</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/share-views-and-join-user-testing-for-iati-s-new-community-platform-november-12th/2037/3</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 17:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6560</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Share views and join user-testing for IATI’s new community platform (November 12th)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@IATI-techteam IATI Technical Team]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Reminder to express your interest in joining the user-testing for IATI’s new community platform (November 12th). We have a few places still available.</p>
<p><strong>1st November deadine</strong></p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/share-views-and-join-user-testing-for-iati-s-new-community-platform-november-12th/2037/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 10:33:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6559</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>[Rejected] New Organisation Identifier: XI-IATI-LFTW</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Michelle_IOM Michelle Levesque]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>May I ask why it matters if the Austrian registration agency is in the org-id guide?  If there is a publicly available registration number from the interior Ministry it seems that is the number that should be used regardless if one cannot go through the Org-ID guide but has to connect directly to the ministry.</p>
<p>How much effort would it take to get the ministry registry into the Org ID guide?</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/rejected-new-organisation-identifier-xi-iati-lftw/2040/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 17:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6558</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Humanitarian Scope - Activity/Transaction Level</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@AVaughn Andie Vaughn]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Colleagues -</p>
<p>Earlier this summer USAID realized that placement of the Humanitarian Scope at the transaction level was causing a critical validation error in the IATI Validator (original post <a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/current-discussion-quantifying-percentage-of-funds-allocated-from-an-activity-to-covid-19/1939/7">here</a>). USAID puts many details (such as country, sector) at the transaction level to improve the granularity of activity information. If we put Humanitarian Scope with the activity level, we will lose significant granularity in our information, as well as dramatically over-count USAID efforts to specific responses. Additionally, elements such as cluster code and glide code can differ among the transactions within one USAID activity.</p>
<p>Initially, USAID decided the best interim solution would be to intentionally continue reporting Humanitarian Scope at the transaction level in order to preserve the granularity of our data. Because this is a critical validation error, however, we have now transitioned to “namespace” the element.</p>
<p>Rather than continue using this workaround, USAID would like to see the IATI standard revised to accommodate the Humanitarian Scope at the transaction level in the same way recipient countries and sectors can be reported at the activity level or transaction level. This will not affect publishers who include this data at the activity level, but will allow for more granularity for those who want to publish transaction-level data. Additionally, we believe this improved granularity will be more useful for data users.</p>
<p>It would be great to discuss this with others.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/humanitarian-scope-activity-transaction-level/2041/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 16:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6557</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>[Rejected] New Organisation Identifier: XI-IATI-LFTW</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@IATI-techteam IATI Technical Team]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>The following addition to the IATI Organisation Identifier list has been proposed for  Light for the World International.</p>
<p><strong>Code:</strong>  XI-IATI-LFTW<br>
<strong>Name:</strong>  Light for the World International<br>
<strong>Description:</strong>   <em>Light for the World is a global disability &amp; development organization that enables crucial eye health services and empower people with disabilities in some of the poorest regions of the world.</em><br>
<strong>URL:</strong> <a href="https://www.light-for-the-world.org/?utm_source=Signature_L-INT&amp;utm_campaign=address_block&amp;utm_medium=Email">www.light-for-the-world.org</a></p>
<p>The organisation is registered in <a href="http://org-id.guide/list/AT-UID">Austria</a> with the Interior Ministry (Bundesministerium Inneres), which is not yet listed on the org-id.guide.</p>
<p>If no objection is received this XI-IATI code will be approved and added in a week.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/rejected-new-organisation-identifier-xi-iati-lftw/2040/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 12:20:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6556</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>IATI Publishing Guidance Pages- How to Suggest Changes - input by 12 October</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@IATI-techteam IATI Technical Team]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Hi everyone,</p>
<p>We have not had further feedback following our response to your comments. We have incorporated the suggestion to change the review period to 6 months and we have added in the additional examples <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1mfbj1HlGavi1AU0nJSJVwxx5_j0lXB8dwV8EiSURvWw/edit#heading=h.s5ha71xbo7cp">to make the document clearer.</a> We would now like to proceed with adding this guidance process next week. If anyone has any additional  feedback or comments please let us know by close of play on Tuesday 27 October. We are also happy to speak to anyone if that is easier!</p>
<p>We do want to reiterate that we are aiming for a pragmatic and workable solution to address a complex issue. This will continue to be a collective effort and we will evaluate the process over time, based on your feedback.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-publishing-guidance-pages-how-to-suggest-changes-input-by-12-october/2020/9</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 12:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6555</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>[Approved] New Organisation Identifier: XI-IATI-SDPI</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@IATI-techteam IATI Technical Team]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>The following addition to the IATI Organisation Identifier list has been proposed for Sustainable Development Policy Institute (SDPI)</p>
<p>No suitable registration code or agency has been found for this organisation.</p>
<p><strong>Code:</strong> XI-IATI-SDPI<br>
<strong>Name:</strong> Sustainable Development Policy Institute (SDPI)<br>
<strong>Description</strong>: The Sustainable Development Policy Institute (SDPI) is an independent non-profit organization that serves as a forum for policy dialogue and provides policy advice to the government. Its research projects focus on five core areas: governance, environment, global and rural livelihoods, human development, and information and communications.<br>
<strong>URL</strong>: <a href="http://www.sdpi.org/">www.sdpi.org</a></p>
<p>Using the <a href="http://org-id.guide/">org-id.guide</a> for the creation of the identifiers <a href="http://org-id.guide/results?structure=all&amp;coverage=PK&amp;sector=all">for Pakistan</a> there are two agencies, but SPDI is not register with neither of them.</p>
<p>If no objection is received this XI-IATI code will be approved and added in a week.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/approved-new-organisation-identifier-xi-iati-sdpi/2039/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 13:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6554</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Share views and join user-testing for IATI’s new community platform (November 12th)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@sanderhees Sander Hees]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Dear Discuss-community,</p>
<p>We have exciting news to share with you! As laid out in IATI’s Workplan 2020, approved by the Governing Board in late 2019, the IATI Secretariat will be launching a new digital community platform by the end of the year. IATI’s new platform will be more inclusive with lots of useful new features. Here are a few:</p>
<p>●	Automated translations of all posts in multiple language;<br>
●	New Communities of Practice where stakeholder groups can discuss their specific open data and IATI needs with their peers;<br>
●	General discussions feature (like IATI Discuss!);<br>
●	A dedicated resource library and training portal;</p>
<p><strong>Oh no - are IATI Discuss posts disappearing??</strong></p>
<p>No, definitely not. We are working to ensure that all content (live and archived) on Discuss will be transferred to the new platform and Discuss users will smoothly transition onto the new platform with as little change to your user experience as possible.<br>
The Secretariat is working hard to plan this transition and Discuss will not be archived until the new platform has been tested, is up and running and working well. The Secretariat will ensure all Discuss users are able to easily move onto the new platform and inform you accordingly.</p>
<p><strong>Share your views and join user-testing on Thursday November 12th</strong></p>
<p>As some of the most active members of our community, your feedback on the new community platform is very valuable. To that end we would like to invite you to an online user testing workshop of the new platform on <strong>Thursday 12th of November 9-10am (NYC), 2-3pm (WAT / UK), 3-4pm (CET)</strong>. We only have limited spaces as we want to ensure a manageable and interactive workshop. Want to join? <em><strong>Express your interest in this user-testing workshop before November 1st via <a href="mailto:sander.hees@undp.org">sander.hees@undp.org</a>.</strong></em></p>
<p>The Secretariat is here to help! Please also share your views or comments on the (technical) migration from Discuss to IATI’s new community-platform with me via <a href="mailto:sander.hees@undp.org">sander.hees@undp.org</a>.<br>
Best,</p>
<p>Sander Hees<br>
Community Facilitator – IATI Secretariat</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/share-views-and-join-user-testing-for-iati-s-new-community-platform-november-12th/2037/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 09:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6552</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reverso validator?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@matmaxgeds Matt Geddes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Hi - would it be possible to have the validator return a list of all the ‘errors’ in IATI data, and then e.g. the number of cases for each one (grouped by error, not by the datafile)? I think the validator stores runs tests on the data in the background so this might be feasible? Or maybe it would be a specific job that looped through all the files - perhaps possible via the validator API?</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/reverso-validator/2033/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 13:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6548</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Publisher ID issue</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@IATI-techteam IATI Technical Team]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Hi <a class="mention" href="/u/sjohns">@SJohns</a>, in this case there were two AidStream accounts set up for the same organisation. The first account was connected to the IATI Registry, which prevented the second one from being connected.</p>
<p>The AidStream devs were able to locate the original account and we could then sort the issue.</p>
<p>If you are struggling to connect your AidStream account to the Registry please do read their <a href="https://github.com/younginnovations/aidstream/wiki/How-do-I-register-to-IATI%3F">user guide</a> or e-mail us at <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a>.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/publisher-id-issue/2030/4</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 07:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6545</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Publisher ID issue</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SJohns SJohns]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Hi <a class="mention" href="/u/iati-techteam">@IATI-techteam</a> It’d be great if you could also post the answer here, in case anyone else has the same problem?</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/publisher-id-issue/2030/3</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 16:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6544</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Publisher ID issue</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@IATI-techteam IATI Technical Team]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Hi Naomi,</p>
<p>Sorry to hear you’re having issues. Please could you send details of your organisation plus a screenshot of what you’re experiencing to <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a>?</p>
<p>We’ll sort you out!</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/publisher-id-issue/2030/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 11:08:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6543</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Publisher ID issue</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@nlr Naomi de Bruijne]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Dear reader,</p>
<p>I have been including transactions for my organization into AIDstream. I tried to publish our data to IATI but I repeatedly receive a pop-up warning that our publisher ID (under registry information) was not correct. However, I don’t understand which publisher ID should be placed, because our IATI publisher ID is somehow not valid.</p>
<p>If anyone can help me in this issue, I look very much forward to your reply. The AIDstream support desk was unfortunately not of any help.</p>
<p>Warm regards from the Netherlands,<br>
Naomi</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/publisher-id-issue/2030/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 13:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-6542</guid>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
