<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Feedback on IATI Public Validator feedback</title>
    <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/feedback-on-iati-public-validator-feedback/1313</link>
    <description>I recently used the IATI Public Validator to check our Organisation file, after a user flagged that it was not validating. 

1- The user provided a link generated by the Validator through the &quot;Share the results&quot; button: http://validator.iatistandard.org/?perm=w05.international.gc.ca_projectbrowser-banqueprojets_iita-iati_dfatd-maecd_organisation.xml_1525333064 (Note that this link has the file path and a string of numbers at the end that look like it may be a unique ID). That link did not work. Its purpose is presumably to go back to a specific validation result, but it did not work. 
 
So I provided the link to our file and sure enough, the Validator said there was a problem. I poked around until I got this feedback on our data: &quot;Line 148 Error 1871 Element &#39;recipient-org-budget&#39;: Element &#39;recipient-org-budget&#39;: This element is not expected. Expected is one of ( recipient-country-budget, document-link, ##other* ).”

2- Our file doesn&#39;t have line numbers, so that reference was not very helpful.

3- What on earth is Error 1871?

4- I understood &quot;Element &#39;recipient-org-budget&#39;: This element is not expected&quot; to mean that the element was not in the standard. However, I checked the standard and found it, so I was lost. I had to turn to the always helpful @andylolz to help me understand what the Validator was saying we were doing wrong (answer: the elements were not in the order dictated by the standard).

As a non-tech person, I found the Validator interface not very friendly and its results/feedback very hard to understand. Perhaps a bit of UX could help improve it?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 15:44:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Data Quality</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/feedback-on-iati-public-validator-feedback/1313.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Feedback on IATI Public Validator feedback</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[YohannaLoucheur]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I recently used the IATI Public Validator to check our Organisation file, after a user flagged that it was not validating.</p>
<p>1- The user provided a link generated by the Validator through the “Share the results” button: <a href="http://validator.iatistandard.org/?perm=w05.international.gc.ca_projectbrowser-banqueprojets_iita-iati_dfatd-maecd_organisation.xml_1525333064">http://validator.iatistandard.org/?perm=w05.international.gc.ca_projectbrowser-banqueprojets_iita-iati_dfatd-maecd_organisation.xml_1525333064</a> (Note that this link has the file path and a string of numbers at the end that look like it may be a unique ID). That link did not work. Its purpose is presumably to go back to a specific validation result, but it did not work.</p>
<p>So I provided the link to our file and sure enough, the Validator said there was a problem. I poked around until I got this feedback on our data: "Line 148 Error 1871 Element ‘recipient-org-budget’: Element ‘recipient-org-budget’: This element is not expected. Expected is one of ( recipient-country-budget, document-link, #<span class="hashtag">#other</span>* ).”</p>
<p>2- Our file doesn’t have line numbers, so that reference was not very helpful.</p>
<p>3- What on earth is Error 1871?</p>
<p>4- I understood “Element ‘recipient-org-budget’: This element is not expected” to mean that the element was not in the standard. However, I checked the standard and found it, so I was lost. I had to turn to the always helpful <a class="mention" href="/u/andylolz">@andylolz</a> to help me understand what the Validator was saying we were doing wrong (answer: the elements were not in the order dictated by the standard).</p>
<p>As a non-tech person, I found the Validator interface not very friendly and its results/feedback very hard to understand. Perhaps a bit of UX could help improve it?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/feedback-on-iati-public-validator-feedback/1313/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/feedback-on-iati-public-validator-feedback/1313/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 15:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-1313-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/feedback-on-iati-public-validator-feedback/1313.rss">Feedback on IATI Public Validator feedback</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
