<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Transaction Type Codelist - Humanitarian Data</title>
    <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/transaction-type-codelist-humanitarian-data/1401</link>
    <description>It would be great to get thoughts and suggestions on the transaction type codelist as we work through how to tag &quot;announced&quot; or &quot;anticipated&quot; commitments in the humanitarian space.  

We have a specific category of transaction that is not considered a &#39;pledge&#39; (which we understand to have specific political meaning), but is not yet a binding, legal financial obligation (what we tag as commitment).  The anticipated funding has merely been &quot;announced.&quot;  Do others have this type of anticipated/announced funding to humanitarian activities that they do not consider to be a &#39;pledge?&#39;  If so, could this be accommodated in the codelist? We would like to publish this data, but are struggling to find a way to do so.

Additionally - as another question, is anyone thinking through how to publish any sort of pledge or announced/anticipated funding when this is a fuzzy number that may change?  For example, an announcement that is $100 one month, but the pledge or announced/anticipated amount increased to $150 the next month - it doesn&#39;t seem like there is a good way to publish this in IATI - it would need to be clear that the total amount is $150 - not $250. Is anyone else discussing this internally or have suggestions?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 18:37:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Codelists</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/transaction-type-codelist-humanitarian-data/1401.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Transaction Type Codelist - Humanitarian Data</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[AVaughn]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>It would be great to get thoughts and suggestions on the transaction type codelist as we work through how to tag “announced” or “anticipated” commitments in the humanitarian space.</p>
<p>We have a specific category of transaction that is not considered a ‘pledge’ (which we understand to have specific political meaning), but is not yet a binding, legal financial obligation (what we tag as commitment).  The anticipated funding has merely been “announced.”  Do others have this type of anticipated/announced funding to humanitarian activities that they do not consider to be a ‘pledge?’  If so, could this be accommodated in the codelist? We would like to publish this data, but are struggling to find a way to do so.</p>
<p>Additionally - as another question, is anyone thinking through how to publish any sort of pledge or announced/anticipated funding when this is a fuzzy number that may change?  For example, an announcement that is $100 one month, but the pledge or announced/anticipated amount increased to $150 the next month - it doesn’t seem like there is a good way to publish this in IATI - it would need to be clear that the total amount is $150 - not $250. Is anyone else discussing this internally or have suggestions?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/transaction-type-codelist-humanitarian-data/1401/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/transaction-type-codelist-humanitarian-data/1401/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 18:37:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-1401-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/transaction-type-codelist-humanitarian-data/1401.rss">Transaction Type Codelist - Humanitarian Data</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
