<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>CSOs - IATI Community Discussions</title>
    <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/c/community-zone/csos/15</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;CSOs&#39; category The IATI CSO Working Group is a place for collaboration and discussion amongst representatives of CSOs who are publishing data to the IATI standard, or intend to in the future. The group also works with the IATI Secretariat to suggest improvements and additions to guidance and documentation to support CSOs publishing IATI data.</description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 15:37:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/c/community-zone/csos/15.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>Fee on AidStream features?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[tanakanyamadzawo]]></dc:creator>
          <category>CSOs</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi all,</p>
<p>Having logged into AidStream earlier, I came across the option of “Unpublish”, with a description over the tab of it being a “paid feature and free users being able to use the feature for a limited period”.</p>
<p>I wondered if anyone else has had heard any more about any upgrades or shifts towards some of AidStream’s features having a fee ?</p>
<p>All the best,</p>
<p>Tanaka</p>
            <p><small>5 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/fee-on-aidstream-features/1882">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/fee-on-aidstream-features/1882</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 15:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1882</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/fee-on-aidstream-features/1882.rss">Fee on AidStream features?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Donor IATI Requirements</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[laia_grino]]></dc:creator>
          <category>CSOs</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>As more and more donors make IATI a requirement for their partners - or consider doing so - we thought it would be helpful to gather information on those official requirements in one place. Below are the requirements issued by the British and Dutch governments. If you know of others, please add!</p>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>UK</strong>: <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/401621/plain_english_minimum_requirements.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener">Plain English explanation of DFID IATI minimum requirements</a>
</li>
<li>
<strong>Netherlands</strong>: <a href="https://www.government.nl/documents/publications/2015/12/01/open-data-and-development-cooperation" rel="nofollow noopener">Open data and development cooperation</a>
</li>
</ul>
            <p><small>6 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/donor-iati-requirements/548">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/donor-iati-requirements/548</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 16:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-548</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/donor-iati-requirements/548.rss">Donor IATI Requirements</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Activity identifiers and synergy between NGOs: how to construct them?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[ACODEV_admin]]></dc:creator>
          <category>CSOs</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>When several NGOs work together for the same outcome, which ID do we need to give for this outcome/activity since the ID activity should be chosen in intern by each organization? In this case, is there any “rule” for writing the ID? Or organizations are free to choose the ID they want? Do they need to insert the ID organization of each organization that are in synergy in the ID activity? I think a fictional example with an ID could help us to understand this issues. Do you have any example for that?</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/activity-identifiers-and-synergy-between-ngos-how-to-construct-them/519">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/activity-identifiers-and-synergy-between-ngos-how-to-construct-them/519</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 14:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-519</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/activity-identifiers-and-synergy-between-ngos-how-to-construct-them/519.rss">Activity identifiers and synergy between NGOs: how to construct them?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Standardised list of local CSO&#39;s in partner countries</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Toon]]></dc:creator>
          <category>CSOs</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello,<br>
not sure if this is the right place to post this…</p>
<p>We would like to standardise in our system the way we encode our CSO-partners in partner countries. We use a freetext field until now, which of course prevents us from reliably querying them. What’s more, we would be very interested to be able to query other organisations’ activity files / data in this respect as well, which I guess would be the case for other development partners too. Hence, a common standardised list would be welcome.</p>
<p>Of course this is linked to various topics, traceability in the first place.</p>
<p>We realise this won’t be easy, given the speed at which the CSO landscape can change. Perhaps we should take a “chaordic” approach as mentioned by Steven (thanks !, interesting) in his post here (<a href="//discuss.iatistandard.org/t/adding-to-the-organisation-registration-agency-code-list-push-rather-than-pull/414?u=toon">Adding to the Organisation Registration Agency code list - push rather than pull?</a>) ?</p>
<p>We were wondering whether there were plans, or appetite, to (try to) assemble such a list at IATI level ?<br>
Would anybody who has experience in this be willing to share the result of their work with us ?</p>
            <p><small>5 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/standardised-list-of-local-csos-in-partner-countries/426">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/standardised-list-of-local-csos-in-partner-countries/426</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 15:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-426</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/standardised-list-of-local-csos-in-partner-countries/426.rss">Standardised list of local CSO&#39;s in partner countries</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>IATI benefits for southern CSOs?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[fiona_waters]]></dc:creator>
          <category>CSOs</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi!</p>
<p>I’d be really interested to hear what you think are the benefits of IATI for CSOs in the global south? particularly those who don’t have the capacity to publish themselves but might be the recipient of funds published by their donor or partner. Any insight into how IATI data can be used by CSOs and partner organisations would be really appreciated.</p>
<p>Thanks!<br>
Fiona</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-benefits-for-southern-csos/398">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-benefits-for-southern-csos/398</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 16:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-398</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-benefits-for-southern-csos/398.rss">IATI benefits for southern CSOs?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Relevance / use of Document Category codes for CSOs</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[stevieflow]]></dc:creator>
          <category>CSOs</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello</p>
<p>I’d like to understand whether the existing DocumentCategory codes are of relevance/use to CSO publishers.  Specifically, the codes that begin with A (applicable to Activities) : <a href="http://iatistandard.org/201/codelists/DocumentCategory/" rel="nofollow noopener">http://iatistandard.org/201/codelists/DocumentCategory/</a></p>
<p>Context - I’ve been working with these documents : <a href="http://www.plan-uk.org/what-we-do/open-info-about-our-projects/africa/" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.plan-uk.org/what-we-do/open-info-about-our-projects/africa/</a> - there is no direct mention of Logframe, Final Report and Proposal in the A-type categories, for example - meaning some interpretation is needed.</p>
<p>Has anyone made a mapping?<br>
Should clarification text be created/added to the existing codes?<br>
Is there a pressing need for new codes?</p>
<p>Whilst I have posted this in the CSO category, this might be applicable to other users.  <a class="mention" href="/u/johnadams">@johnadams</a> might have ideas…</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/relevance-use-of-document-category-codes-for-csos/312">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/relevance-use-of-document-category-codes-for-csos/312</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 14:16:39 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-312</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/relevance-use-of-document-category-codes-for-csos/312.rss">Relevance / use of Document Category codes for CSOs</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Lets promote the use of data - CSO &quot;Action group&quot; launched</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Claudia_Schwegmann]]></dc:creator>
          <category>CSOs</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Dear all, after all the discussions around use of data, or rather the lack of data use at the IATI TAG in Ottawa Mai 2015, some CSOs want to work on this. This idea is also a follow up of the CSO meeting ahead of the TAG. We will have a first Skype call on the 8th of July. The time is not entirely set - either at 14 hrs CET or at 16 hrs CET. I will update you as soon as possible on the date.<br>
I realize that there is no working group on data use. My sense is that this is something that is really needed now. I suggest that we discuss this on the Skype call as well.<br>
A last issue to address urgently: we do not have a list of examples of data use (as far as I know). For outreach, awareness raising, advocacy, etc. such a list is really important. The easiest way would be to just start with a google doc and collect examples. To get us going, I have started a google doc: <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1MA3Mqu5yPlD_AGAorEJ7apQ5xjpNV1JIHT5s0Acb36k/edit" rel="nofollow noopener">https://docs.google.com/document/d/1MA3Mqu5yPlD_AGAorEJ7apQ5xjpNV1JIHT5s0Acb36k/edit</a><br>
PLEASE add examples, that you are familiar with and share the doc with others who may be able to add examples!</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/lets-promote-the-use-of-data-cso-action-group-launched/289">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/lets-promote-the-use-of-data-cso-action-group-launched/289</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 07:03:11 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-289</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/lets-promote-the-use-of-data-cso-action-group-launched/289.rss">Lets promote the use of data - CSO &quot;Action group&quot; launched</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Sharing data responsibly - webinar, 2 December</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[JoniHillman]]></dc:creator>
          <category>CSOs</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>FROM INTERACTION:</p>
<p>Dear Colleagues,</p>
<p>As organizations undertake efforts to be more open and transparent – including by sharing data on <a href="http://www.ngoaidmap.org/">NGO Aid Map</a> or publishing data to IATI – how to efficiently prevent sensitive information from being made public is often a key concern. Please join us for a webinar on Tuesday, December 2 from 10:00-10:45 am with the UK Department for International Development (DFID) and the United Nations Development Programme (UNDP), who will share their experiences with balancing transparency with privacy, security and other concerns. You can register for the webinar <a href="https://attendee.gotowebinar.com/register/200000000028929515">here</a>.</p>
<p>John Adams, Head of DFID’s Business Innovation Team, will share:<br>
•     DFID’s exclusions principles and policy: how Freedom of Information (FOI) principles translate into an exclusions model<br>
•     How this works in practice: how we make sure that our systems do not release excluded data<br>
•     What else needs to be done?<br>
Mark Cardwell, Chief of Online Communications at UNDP, will explain:<br>
•         UNDP’s disclosure polices: how to create a culture of transparency while understanding risks<br>
•         T‎ools and techniques to support smart, safe transparency<br>
•         Next steps for transparency</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/sharing-data-responsibly-webinar-2-december/117">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/sharing-data-responsibly-webinar-2-december/117</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 14:16:05 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-117</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/sharing-data-responsibly-webinar-2-december/117.rss">Sharing data responsibly - webinar, 2 December</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>IATI implementation materials for CSO&#39;s Partos</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaspermid]]></dc:creator>
          <category>CSOs</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <ul>
<li>As I can only post 10 links please see <a href="https://partos.nl/content/iati-training-materials" rel="nofollow noopener">https://partos.nl/content/iati-training-materials</a> for the complete list (and latest versions) of the training materials</li>
</ul>
<p>Hi everyone,</p>
<p>At Partos we started with our IATI training programme in may 2013 with a support programme for Dutch NGO’s. As we’ve learned a lot about a structured approach to IATI publication I created this posts to share what we’ve learned and the training materials we are using.  Central in our approach is a focus on high quality data sets and the practical uses of IATI data for individual organisations. For this support we have developed and are developing tools that help organisation structure their IATI process. Big thanks to Rolf Kleef and Pelle Aardema from Open for Change with whom we created these tools.</p>
<p>We started with enhancing the implementation schedule so it can serve as a step-by step guide to IATI implementation. The renewed implementation schedule helps organisation to structure their IATI implementation proces along four main steps. Starting to publish, planning to publish, data mapping and getting ready to publish. The Partos training programme is structured along the lines of these steps.</p>
<p><a href="https://partos.nl/system/files/ckeditor/files/Implementation%20Schedule%20for%20NGO%27s.xls" rel="nofollow noopener">Implementation schedule download</a></p>
<p><strong>Starting to publish</strong><br>
During the starting to publish seminar we help organisations in their first steps towards IATI publication. In this session we organise workshops around getting to know international stakeholders. We do this through customer journeys and persona templates.</p>
<p><em>Training materials :</em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://partos.nl/system/files/ckeditor/files/20140612%20Partos%20IATI%20-%2024%20June%20Starting%20Up%20-%20facilitator%20scheme.docx" rel="nofollow noopener">Facilitator schedule (timetable)</a></li>
<li>Presentation from zero to IATI in 15(ish) minutes (Dutch)</li>
<li>Presentation Pelle Aardema, 7 uses of IATI data</li>
<li><a href="https://partos.nl/system/files/ckeditor/files/IATI%20Customer%20journey.docx" rel="nofollow noopener">Customer Journey</a></li>
<li><a href="https://partos.nl/system/files/ckeditor/files/Persona%20template.docx" rel="nofollow noopener">Persona Template</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Planning to publish<br>
The planning to publish session is meant to help organisations with their roadmap towards IATI, including the licenses, exclusion and external partners that need to be involved.</p>
<p>Training materials:</p>
<ul>
<li>Presentation Rolf Kleef, Introduction &amp; planning (odp)</li>
<li>Presentation Pelle Aardema, Planning publication, creating a roadmap</li>
<li>Presentation Rolf, Exclusions &amp; licenses (odp)</li>
<li><a href="https://partos.nl/system/files/ckeditor/files/20140909%20-%20Planning%20your%20IATI%20project.pptx" rel="nofollow noopener">Example planning template (courtesy of Red Cross Netherlands)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://partos.nl/system/files/ckeditor/files/Planning%20IATI%20project%20-%20A2.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener">Empty planning template</a></li>
<li>Cordaid Example data use in communication folder</li>
<li><a href="https://partos.nl/system/files/ckeditor/files/20140909-Exercise-project%281%29.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener">Exclusion poster exercise template</a></li>
<li>How to set up your prototype session</li>
<li><a href="https://partos.nl/system/files/ckeditor/files/Prototype%20template_IATI%20fields%20simplified.xlsx" rel="nofollow noopener">Simplified overview of IATI fields &amp; Prototyping template</a></li>
<li><a href="https://partos.nl/system/files/ckeditor/files/20140909-IATI-step-2-exclusions-permissions.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener">Facilitator schedule (timetable)</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Data Mapping</strong><br>
Data Mapping is focused on helping organisations link their organisational information to the IATI fields. Central in our approach is to create a prototype data set in Aidstream through which the challenges and road towards a high qualitty IATI data set.</p>
<p><em>Training materials :</em><br>
Will be published after the third session of our second round support</p>
<p><strong>Getting ready to publish, use of data</strong><br>
Getting Ready to publish seminar will be focused around seting up publisher accounts and the practical uses of data.</p>
<p>Training materials :<br>
Will be published after the fourth session of our second round support</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-implementation-materials-for-csos-partos/107">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-implementation-materials-for-csos-partos/107</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 14:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-107</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-implementation-materials-for-csos-partos/107.rss">IATI implementation materials for CSO&#39;s Partos</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Next IATI Steering Committee 15-16 October 2014</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[SJohns]]></dc:creator>
          <category>CSOs</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The next Steering Committee meeting will take place on 15-16 October 2014 at UN City in Copenhagen, Denmark. There will be a Partner Country Caucus on 14 October, also in Copenhagen. - See more at: <a href="http://www.aidtransparency.net/governance/steering-committee#sthash.rqTSCrKi.dpuf" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.aidtransparency.net/governance/steering-committee#sthash.rqTSCrKi.dpuf</a></p>
<p>The agenda is filling up quickly, and so if the CSO group want to make representations to have items added to the agenda, we need to start now.</p>
<p>Please use this topic to add your ideas and comments. For example, I’d like to see us present best practice for donor governments who are planning on requiring NGOs to use IATI, and potential benefits that NGOs bring to  IATI data, for example traceability.</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/next-iati-steering-committee-15-16-october-2014/89">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/next-iati-steering-committee-15-16-october-2014/89</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 13:34:02 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-89</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/next-iati-steering-committee-15-16-october-2014/89.rss">Next IATI Steering Committee 15-16 October 2014</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Overview Of CSO Working Group</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy]]></dc:creator>
          <category>CSOs</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The IATI CSO Working Group was originally created in September 2011 as part of the IATI Technical Advisory Group (TAG) to ensure that CSOs’ perspectives were adequately represented. The goals of this newly revitalized working group are to represent CSO perspectives on IATI, to discuss the application of the IATI standard to the work of CSOs, and to present practical proposals on CSO-specific approaches to publication of IATI compatible data.</p>
<p>This group’s focus is specifically on IATI, but its work is guided by the Istanbul Principles (IP) and the International Framework on CSO Development Effectiveness (IF), which are an expression of CSOs’ commitment to transparency and accountability. This group will coordinate closely with other groups working on CSO transparency, particularly around points of complementarity between IATI and other CSO transparency initiatives.</p>
<p><strong>Objectives</strong></p>
<p>The objectives of the group are as follows:</p>
<ol>
<li>To increase awareness of IATI among CSOs, not only in terms of<br>
publication of IATI data but also in terms of the use of this data…</li>
<li>To provide CSOs with up-to-date information on IATI debates and<br>
developments that are relevant to them.</li>
<li>To establish a feedback channel with IATI that allows CSOs to take<br>
some ownership of the process, in particular related to CSO issues<br>
of concern.</li>
<li>To identify and attempt to address challenges faced by CSOs<br>
implementing IATI, including through the development of guidance<br>
materials, for example. Given that many other actors are engaged in<br>
similar efforts, the working group may largely play a coordinating<br>
role in this area.</li>
<li>To serve as a forum for information exchange for organizations<br>
encouraging the use of or publishing to IATI.</li>
<li>To contribute to the evolution and development of the IATI standard,<br>
to ensure it reflects ways of working of CSOs (for those<br>
publishing), as well as CSO information needs. This could include<br>
potential extensions to the IATI standard.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Resources</strong></p>
<p>The following documents are available below:</p>
<ul>
<li>Working Group Terms of Reference</li>
<li>Working Group Announcement (Busan, November 2011)</li>
</ul>
<p><a class="attachment" href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/uploads/default/27/450744ae1526575d.docx">IATI CSO Working Group TOR - Sept 2013.docx</a> (14.9 KB)</p>
<p><a class="attachment" href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/uploads/default/33/22bfe66171e44555.doc">IATI TAG CSO Working Group Announcement (Nov 2011 Busan, Korea).doc</a> (76.5 KB)</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/overview-of-cso-working-group/81">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/overview-of-cso-working-group/81</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 10:51:41 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-81</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/overview-of-cso-working-group/81.rss">Overview Of CSO Working Group</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Results of the Rendir Cuentas Consultation on IATI - April 2012</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy]]></dc:creator>
          <category>CSOs</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>In April 2012, the heads of the country partner organizations of Rendir Cuentas, met in Lima for a day of consultation prior to the IATI CSO Working Group in the UK during May.</p>
<p>This document is a summary of the main conclusions, agreements and proposals of their consultation : <a href="http://www.interaction.org/document/rendir-cuentas-results-latin-american-iati-consultation">http://www.interaction.org/document/rendir-cuentas-results-latin-american-iati-consultation</a></p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/results-of-the-rendir-cuentas-consultation-on-iati-april-2012/80">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/results-of-the-rendir-cuentas-consultation-on-iati-april-2012/80</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 10:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-80</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/results-of-the-rendir-cuentas-consultation-on-iati-april-2012/80.rss">Results of the Rendir Cuentas Consultation on IATI - April 2012</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Background Paper: Civil Society Organisations and International NGOS: Ways Forward in Implementation of the IATI Standard</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy]]></dc:creator>
          <category>CSOs</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This paper is the first piece of work by the IATI CSO Working Group, addressing the challenges and options for solutions for CSOs publishing IATI data.</p>
<p><a class="attachment" href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/uploads/default/30/3e581331bc9dbfb8.doc">Final June 2012 IATI Background Paper.doc</a> (390 KB)</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/background-paper-civil-society-organisations-and-international-ngos-ways-forward-in-implementation-of-the-iati-standard/79">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/background-paper-civil-society-organisations-and-international-ngos-ways-forward-in-implementation-of-the-iati-standard/79</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 10:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-79</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/background-paper-civil-society-organisations-and-international-ngos-ways-forward-in-implementation-of-the-iati-standard/79.rss">Background Paper: Civil Society Organisations and International NGOS: Ways Forward in Implementation of the IATI Standard</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Implementing the International Aid Transparency Initiative (IATI) Standard by CSOs: A Protocol</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy]]></dc:creator>
          <category>CSOs</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This protocol was developed under the auspices of the IATI CSO Working Group in November 2012. It is addressed to all donors, governments and non-state actors implementing the Busan common standard. It establishes principles to guide CSO implementation of the IATI Standard, the enabling conditions for CSOs to implement this Standard, and outlines the parameters for the engagement of CSOs in jointly promoting the implementation of the IATI Standard with other aid actors.</p>
<p><a class="attachment" href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/uploads/default/29/2639321a9cf3eb22.pdf">Final November CSO IATI Protocol.pdf</a> (172.3 KB)</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/implementing-the-international-aid-transparency-initiative-iati-standard-by-csos-a-protocol/78">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/implementing-the-international-aid-transparency-initiative-iati-standard-by-csos-a-protocol/78</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 10:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-78</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/implementing-the-international-aid-transparency-initiative-iati-standard-by-csos-a-protocol/78.rss">Implementing the International Aid Transparency Initiative (IATI) Standard by CSOs: A Protocol</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>CSO Working Group meeting 28 Jan 2014, Montreal</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy]]></dc:creator>
          <category>CSOs</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The first 2014 meeting of the IATI CSO Working Group meeting was held on Tuesday 28 Jan 2014 in the 4th floor meeting room at Development and Peace, 1425 René-Lévesque Blvd West, 3rd Floor Montréal QC  H3G 1T7.  The agenda can be downloaded below.  Updates from members of the CSO Working Group, and the notes for this meeting can be found at:</p>
<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1SPzKvlNJK5xPqSSszOZr00EDgqlWlCO" rel="nofollow noopener">https://docs.google.com/document/d/1SPzKvlNJK5xPqSSszOZr00EDgqlWlCO</a>…</p>
<p>There was also a session on CSO Guidance at the TAG 2014 at 11:45am Weds 29 Jan 2014. The notes can be found at: <a href="http://www.aidtransparency.net/governance/tag/tag-meeting-2014/tag-" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.aidtransparency.net/governance/tag/tag-meeting-2014/tag-</a>… and then chose the right session.</p>
<p><a class="attachment" href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/uploads/default/28/93e0e6c96d0b3561.docx">IATI CSO Working Group Meeting - Final Agenda.docx</a> (21.5 KB)</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/cso-working-group-meeting-28-jan-2014-montreal/77">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/cso-working-group-meeting-28-jan-2014-montreal/77</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 10:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-77</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/cso-working-group-meeting-28-jan-2014-montreal/77.rss">CSO Working Group meeting 28 Jan 2014, Montreal</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>How to join the IATI civil society Working Group</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy]]></dc:creator>
          <category>CSOs</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>You can join the IATI CSO Working Group by going to this link: <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1Cfm4SKe7nEF-TSwx_otbqWtC-fNLNnah4jL8hDgx1Nk/viewform">https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1Cfm4SKe7nEF-TSwx_otbqWtC-fNLNnah4jL8hDgx1Nk/viewform</a></p>
<p>The Group is free to join for any civil society organisation (CSO) or non-governmental organisation (NGO) who is:</p>
<ul>
<li>Publishing or planning to publish to IATI;</li>
<li>Increase awareness of IATI   among CSOs;</li>
<li>Advocating for the use of the IATI standard among CSOs;</li>
<li>Providing technical support to CSOs on implementation of the IATI<br>
standard;</li>
<li>or Working to facilitate the use of IATI data by CSOs. This includes<br>
efforts to increase awareness of IATI as a source of information,<br>
build organizations’ capacity to use aid information, develop tools<br>
to make IATI data more accessible, etc</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Objectives (for full Terms of Reference for the group, go to <a href="http://is.gd/6oRi3P">http://is.gd/6oRi3P</a></strong></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>To increase awareness of IATI among CSOs, not only in terms of<br>
publication of IATI data but also in terms of the use of this data.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>To provide CSOs with up-to-date information on IATI debates and<br>
developments that are relevant to them.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>To establish a feedback channel with IATI that allows CSOs to take<br>
some ownership of the process, in particular related to CSO issues<br>
of concern.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>To identify and attempt to address challenges faced by CSOs<br>
implementing IATI, including through the development of guidance<br>
materials, for example. Given that many other actors are engaged in<br>
similar efforts, the working group may largely play a coordinating<br>
role in this area.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>To serve as a forum for information exchange for organizations<br>
encouraging the use of or publishing to IATI.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>To contribute to the evolution and development of the IATI standard,<br>
to ensure it reflects ways of working of CSOs (for those<br>
publishing), as well as CSO information needs. This could include<br>
potential extensions to the IATI standard.</p>
</li>
</ol>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/how-to-join-the-iati-civil-society-working-group/76">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/how-to-join-the-iati-civil-society-working-group/76</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 10:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-76</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/how-to-join-the-iati-civil-society-working-group/76.rss">How to join the IATI civil society Working Group</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>About the CSOs category</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[JoniHillman]]></dc:creator>
          <category>CSOs</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The IATI CSO Working Group is a place for collaboration and discussion amongst representatives of CSOs who are publishing data to the IATI standard, or intend to in the future. The group also works with the IATI Secretariat to suggest improvements and additions to guidance and documentation to support CSOs publishing IATI data.</p>
<p><strong>Membership</strong><br>
Membership of the group is open to anyone who is involved or interested in CSO IATI publication.</p>
<p><strong>Co-Chairs</strong><br>
The group is co-chaired by:</p>
<ul>
<li>Laia Grino, InterAction (USA)</li>
<li>Sarah Johns, Bond (UK)</li>
</ul>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/about-the-csos-category/67">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/about-the-csos-category/67</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 14:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>Yes</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-67</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/about-the-csos-category/67.rss">About the CSOs category</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
