<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>IATI submitted to UK Open Standards process</title>
    <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-submitted-to-uk-open-standards-process/526</link>
    <description>We are processing the IATI Standard through the UK Government Open Standards process. This process goes through [four different stages](https://standards.data.gov.uk/), and is currently in the Response stage, seeking solutions from experts (you good people!) to meet the user need described in the Suggestion stage. 

In the Response stage, I have suggested that IATI meets the user need for openly sharing information on international development. Can I encourage you (particularly if you are resident in the UK) now to contribute your support to that response, over the next few days. You can [submit the response here](https://standards.data.gov.uk/challenge/open-standard-international-development-data).

Thanks 

John</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 13:08:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Community Zone</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-submitted-to-uk-open-standards-process/526.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>IATI submitted to UK Open Standards process</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[JohnAdams]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>We are processing the IATI Standard through the UK Government Open Standards process. This process goes through <a href="https://standards.data.gov.uk/">four different stages</a>, and is currently in the Response stage, seeking solutions from experts (you good people!) to meet the user need described in the Suggestion stage.</p>
<p>In the Response stage, I have suggested that IATI meets the user need for openly sharing information on international development. Can I encourage you (particularly if you are resident in the UK) now to contribute your support to that response, over the next few days. You can <a href="https://standards.data.gov.uk/challenge/open-standard-international-development-data">submit the response here</a>.</p>
<p>Thanks</p>
<p>John</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-submitted-to-uk-open-standards-process/526/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-submitted-to-uk-open-standards-process/526/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 19:42:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-526-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-submitted-to-uk-open-standards-process/526.rss">IATI submitted to UK Open Standards process</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
