<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Consultant required for IATI data use research and analysis</title>
    <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/consultant-required-for-iati-data-use-research-and-analysis/492</link>
    <description>IATI Secretariat member [Development Initiatives](http://devinit.org/#!/) (DI) is looking for an experienced consultant to work for up to 10 days between July and September 2016 to undertake a systematic analysis of existing **IATI data use**. Use cases and user categories, as well as the opportunities and challenges encountered by data users, will be included in a study by the consultant. The study will synthesise and systematise existing experience, building on previous work rather than starting from scratch.

The consultant should be able to demonstrate a strong knowledge of, and familiarity with, IATI and the wider data for development/data revolution agenda.

The qualification criteria and timeframe, as well as details on how to apply, are provided on DI’s [vacancies page](http://devinit.org/#!/about/vacancies).**The deadline to submit applications is 28 June 2016.**</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 13:31:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Notifications</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/consultant-required-for-iati-data-use-research-and-analysis/492.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Consultant required for IATI data use research and analysis</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[JoniHillman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>IATI Secretariat member <a href="http://devinit.org/#!/">Development Initiatives</a> (DI) is looking for an experienced consultant to work for up to 10 days between July and September 2016 to undertake a systematic analysis of existing <strong>IATI data use</strong>. Use cases and user categories, as well as the opportunities and challenges encountered by data users, will be included in a study by the consultant. The study will synthesise and systematise existing experience, building on previous work rather than starting from scratch.</p>
<p>The consultant should be able to demonstrate a strong knowledge of, and familiarity with, IATI and the wider data for development/data revolution agenda.</p>
<p>The qualification criteria and timeframe, as well as details on how to apply, are provided on DI’s <a href="http://devinit.org/#!/about/vacancies">vacancies page</a>.<strong>The deadline to submit applications is 28 June 2016.</strong></p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/consultant-required-for-iati-data-use-research-and-analysis/492/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/consultant-required-for-iati-data-use-research-and-analysis/492/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 10:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-492-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/consultant-required-for-iati-data-use-research-and-analysis/492.rss">Consultant required for IATI data use research and analysis</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
