<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>IATI and M&amp;E Software</title>
    <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-and-m-e-software/1371</link>
    <description>Hi everyone! 

I have just joined the IATI community and I&#39;ve seen a lot of knowledge and resource sharing going on here, so I also want to offer myself as a resource for those looking into M&amp;E software with IATI export capabilities. 

I work at [DevResults](http://www.devresults.com), we deliver purpose-built M&amp;E software for global development. We 100% believe that information &amp; transparency can move the ball in international development, which is why we enable our users to export their data into IATI format in just one-click! This has been a very important function for the organizations that we work with who want to share their results data to add to the body of knowledge about what&#39;s working and what&#39;s not in development work!

If you have questions about DevResults and how we enable organizations to publish their results, feel free to email me directly at tumisang@devresults.com or comment on here!

Thanks!

Tumisang</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 22:10:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Community Zone</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-and-m-e-software/1371.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>IATI and M&amp;E Software</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Tumisang]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi everyone!</p>
<p>I have just joined the IATI community and I’ve seen a lot of knowledge and resource sharing going on here, so I also want to offer myself as a resource for those looking into M&amp;E software with IATI export capabilities.</p>
<p>I work at <a href="http://www.devresults.com" rel="nofollow noopener">DevResults</a>, we deliver purpose-built M&amp;E software for global development. We 100% believe that information &amp; transparency can move the ball in international development, which is why we enable our users to export their data into IATI format in just one-click! This has been a very important function for the organizations that we work with who want to share their results data to add to the body of knowledge about what’s working and what’s not in development work!</p>
<p>If you have questions about DevResults and how we enable organizations to publish their results, feel free to email me directly at <a href="mailto:tumisang@devresults.com">tumisang@devresults.com</a> or comment on here!</p>
<p>Thanks!</p>
<p>Tumisang</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-and-m-e-software/1371/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-and-m-e-software/1371/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 17:27:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-post-1371-1</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-and-m-e-software/1371.rss">IATI and M&amp;E Software</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
