<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Notifications - IATI Community Discussions</title>
    <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/c/notifications/29</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;Notifications&#39; category The IATI Technical Team will post information here to let the IATI community know about IATI related issues.</description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 17:07:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/c/notifications/29.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>Discuss is going into read-only mode</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Dear Discuss-community,</p>
<p>As you know we will be migrating this platform, both content and users, to the new IATI Connect platform. As of  <strong>Wednesday 25 of November - 12pm (GMT/UTC)  IATI Discuss will be in read-only mode</strong>. This allows us to move all content over for the launch on the 30th.</p>
<p>The new IATI Connect will have:</p>
<ul>
<li>A dedicated space for the Discuss-Archive (containing our current Discuss and a link to existing archive);</li>
<li>Ongoing / specific discussions will be integrated into the new IATI Communities, and would hopefully provide an opportunity to widen the audience and embed it into the wider IATI discussions;</li>
<li>IATI-wide consultations and technical discussions, such as the Standard Management category, will be housed under the IATI Connect Consultations;</li>
</ul>
<p>What does this mean for you in practice?</p>
<ul>
<li>Every migration takes some time. Therefore, as of Wednesday 25th of November - 12pm (GMT/UTC) the Discuss-content and users will be ‘on the move’. Any changes made on Discuss post 12pm (should be disabled) and will definitely not be moved across to the new platform.</li>
<li>You will all receive a notification (by email) once we have arrived at our new location: IATI Connect. Through that notification you will be assigned a new profile on the platform (which is pre-arranged) and additional relevant onboarding information.</li>
<li>IATI Discuss will stay in read-only mode for 6 months before being removed. This will allow us time to make sure no content is lost and is findable on the new platform.</li>
</ul>
<p>Once you access your profile, you’ll be able to join a Community of Practice, register for events, contribute to discussions, see other content specific to those groups, and much more.</p>
<p>Of course we hope everything will go smoothly, but every migration is exciting. In case you have any questions or comments please send us an email through <a href="mailto:connect@iatistandard.org">connect@iatistandard.org</a>.</p>
<p>Thank you for your understanding, and we look forward to seeing you ‘on the other side’.</p>
<p>Best,</p>
<p>IATI Secretariat</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/discuss-is-going-into-read-only-mode/2054">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/discuss-is-going-into-read-only-mode/2054</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 17:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-2054</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/discuss-is-going-into-read-only-mode/2054.rss">Discuss is going into read-only mode</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Launch IATI Connect and COPs (Monday November 30th)</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[sanderhees]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Dear Discuss-community,</p>
<p>As you know, on Monday November 30th we will be launching IATI’s first Communities of Practice and IATI Connect-platform (which will also provide space for the Discuss-archive and active threads).</p>
<p>Are you ready to Connect? We have 125 registered participants for the launch-event, but registration is still open! Check out our latest animation announcing the COP-launch and how you can register:</p>
<div class="onebox lazyYT lazyYT-container" data-youtube-id="I661FrMxmLE" data-youtube-title="IATI Communities of Practice launch (with subtitles)" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque">
  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I661FrMxmLE" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">
    <img class="ytp-thumbnail-image" src="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/I661FrMxmLE/maxresdefault.jpg" title="IATI Communities of Practice launch (with subtitles)" width="690" height="388">
  </a>
</div>

            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/launch-iati-connect-and-cops-monday-november-30th/2051">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/launch-iati-connect-and-cops-monday-november-30th/2051</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 06:42:22 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-2051</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/launch-iati-connect-and-cops-monday-november-30th/2051.rss">Launch IATI Connect and COPs (Monday November 30th)</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Share views and join user-testing for IATI’s new community platform (November 12th)</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[sanderhees]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Dear Discuss-community,</p>
<p>We have exciting news to share with you! As laid out in IATI’s Workplan 2020, approved by the Governing Board in late 2019, the IATI Secretariat will be launching a new digital community platform by the end of the year. IATI’s new platform will be more inclusive with lots of useful new features. Here are a few:</p>
<p>●	Automated translations of all posts in multiple language;<br>
●	New Communities of Practice where stakeholder groups can discuss their specific open data and IATI needs with their peers;<br>
●	General discussions feature (like IATI Discuss!);<br>
●	A dedicated resource library and training portal;</p>
<p><strong>Oh no - are IATI Discuss posts disappearing??</strong></p>
<p>No, definitely not. We are working to ensure that all content (live and archived) on Discuss will be transferred to the new platform and Discuss users will smoothly transition onto the new platform with as little change to your user experience as possible.<br>
The Secretariat is working hard to plan this transition and Discuss will not be archived until the new platform has been tested, is up and running and working well. The Secretariat will ensure all Discuss users are able to easily move onto the new platform and inform you accordingly.</p>
<p><strong>Share your views and join user-testing on Thursday November 12th</strong></p>
<p>As some of the most active members of our community, your feedback on the new community platform is very valuable. To that end we would like to invite you to an online user testing workshop of the new platform on <strong>Thursday 12th of November 9-10am (NYC), 2-3pm (WAT / UK), 3-4pm (CET)</strong>. We only have limited spaces as we want to ensure a manageable and interactive workshop. Want to join? <em><strong>Express your interest in this user-testing workshop before November 1st via <a href="mailto:sander.hees@undp.org">sander.hees@undp.org</a>.</strong></em></p>
<p>The Secretariat is here to help! Please also share your views or comments on the (technical) migration from Discuss to IATI’s new community-platform with me via <a href="mailto:sander.hees@undp.org">sander.hees@undp.org</a>.<br>
Best,</p>
<p>Sander Hees<br>
Community Facilitator – IATI Secretariat</p>
            <p><small>8 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/share-views-and-join-user-testing-for-iati-s-new-community-platform-november-12th/2037">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/share-views-and-join-user-testing-for-iati-s-new-community-platform-november-12th/2037</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 09:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-2037</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/share-views-and-join-user-testing-for-iati-s-new-community-platform-november-12th/2037.rss">Share views and join user-testing for IATI’s new community platform (November 12th)</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>IATI&#39;s Datastore and Validator Tools launched</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>IATI is delighted to announce the launch today of its new <a href="https://iatidatastore.iatistandard.org/home">Datastore</a> and <a href="https://iativalidator.iatistandard.org/">Validator</a>, fulfilling a commitment to members to provide robust tools to improve the quality and use of development and humanitarian data published to IATI.</p>
<ol>
<li>Why use the new IATI Datastore?</li>
<li>Why use the new IATI Validator?</li>
<li>Get support: online guidance and webinars</li>
<li>What’s changed since the testing phase?</li>
<li>Deprecation of old Datastore and Public Validator - 22 March 2021</li>
<li>Upcoming work</li>
</ol>
<p>Developing and building these new tools has been the result of a close collaboration between the IATI Secretariat and suppliers Zimmerman and Data4Development, and thanks are also due to our dedicated community for testing the new tools and helping us to improve them.</p>
<p>The following information is provided to enable our community of publishers and users to easily transition to using the new tools and get help through webinars and detailed guidance. It also outlines planning for subsequent phases of development to continually improve our suite of IATI tools.</p>
<h3>Why use the new IATI Datastore?</h3>
<p>The new IATI Datastore allows for much more detailed queries and searches of IATI data than previously possible. Use the <a href="https://iatidatastore.iatistandard.org/querybuilder/core-filters">Query Builder</a> to search data across 39 different fields (elements and attributes) of the IATI Standard and choose to download data in three different formats (CSV, XML and JSON). For the more technical user, the <a href="https://iatidatastore.iatistandard.org/documentation">Datastore API</a> enables searches of IATI data across  <strong>all</strong>  elements of the IATI Standard, enabling more complex data analysis.</p>
<p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://iatistandard.org/media/images/IATI_Datastore_Query_Builder.width-700.png" title="IATI Datastore Query Builder launch.png|autoxauto"><img src="https://iatistandard.org/media/images/IATI_Datastore_Query_Builder.width-700.png" alt="IATI Datastore Query Builder launch.png|autoxauto" width="676" height="500"><div class="meta"><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">IATI Datastore Query Builder launch.png|autoxauto</span><span class="informations">700×517</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg></div></a></div></p>
<p>Use the Query Builder to search for development and humanitarian activities responding to COVID-19</p>
<p>The Query Builder and API also provide users with data that complies with the most up-to-date version of the IATI Standard (version 2 and beyond). The IATI Datastore complements existing online tools for accessing IATI data such as <a href="http://d-portal.org/ctrack.html#view=search">d-portal</a>.</p>
<h3>Why use the new IATI Validator?</h3>
<p>Organisations are strongly encouraged to use the new IATI Validator to check if their data is accessible and of good quality, increasing its utility for partner countries, civil society and other data users. Organisations have the option of <a href="https://iativalidator.iatistandard.org/validate">checking for errors in their data  <em>before</em>  publishing their files</a>, or  <em>after</em>  data has been published (<a href="https://iativalidator.iatistandard.org/organisations">using the Public Data Viewer</a>).</p>
<p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://iatistandard.org/media/images/IATI_Validator_launch.width-700.png" title="IATI Validator launch.png|autoxauto"><img src="https://iatistandard.org/media/images/IATI_Validator_launch.width-700.png" alt="IATI Validator launch.png|autoxauto" width="690" height="363"><div class="meta"><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">IATI Validator launch.png|autoxauto</span><span class="informations">700×369</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg></div></a></div></p>
<p>Use the new <a href="https://iativalidator.iatistandard.org/">IATI Validator</a> to check the quality of IATI data.</p>
<p>Most organisations will find at least some errors in their data and we know this may take some time for them to correct. IATI’s Secretariat is providing support in the following ways to help organisations make these changes to improve the quality of their data.</p>
<h3>Get support: online guidance and webinars</h3>
<p>The IATI Secretariat has provided instructions and useful information on both tools through online guidance: <a href="https://iatistandard.org/documents/10453/IATI_Datastore_Query_Builder_User_Guide.pdf">IATI Datastore Query Builder User Guide</a>, <a href="https://iatidatastore.iatistandard.org/documentation">IATI Datastore API documentation</a> and the <a href="https://iatistandard.org/documents/10454/IATI_Validator_QA_September_2020.pdf">IATI Validator Q&amp;A</a>. The Secretariat will also be proactively contacting IATI publishers in the coming months to offer direct support to improve their datafiles using the IATI Validator.</p>
<p>You can learn how to make the most of both tools by joining upcoming webinars held by IATI’s Technical Team:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>Webinar: Using IATI’s new Validator, Wednesday 7 October</strong>  <a href="https://zoom.us/meeting/register/tJcof-GhqjkrEtOQfRStOf1mTknhe_yguTkj"> <strong>Register</strong> </a>
</li>
<li>
<strong>Webinar: Using IATI’s new Datastore, Wednesday 28 October</strong>  <a href="https://zoom.us/meeting/register/tJIrduqpqzMuHtLCjFMrqiBt5HM3HUBRU0GG"> <strong>Register</strong> </a>
</li>
</ul>
<p>As always, the IATI Technical Team welcomes your questions and feedback at: <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a>.</p>
<h3>What’s changed since the testing phase?</h3>
<p>The new Datastore and Validator were pre-released for extensive testing. Both have benefitted from a huge number of improvements in response to feedback from IATI’s community of data users and publishers. Here are just a few examples:</p>
<p><strong>Datastore</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Additional filters have been added to the Datastore Query Builder</li>
<li>Users can now output CSV columns in the order of the IATI XML Schema</li>
<li>The Query Builder has a new multi-sector and multi-country expansion option</li>
<li>The Datastore is now integrated with the Validator. This means that the Validator will check that data is fed into the Datastore and ensure only data that follows the IATI schema is available to users. The IATI schema provides the exact order and structure for publishing the XML. Data that does not follow the IATI XML schema will not be outputted through the Datastore. For further information see <a href="https://iatistandard.org/documents/10454/IATI_Validator_QA_September_2020.pdf">IATI Validator Q&amp;A</a> (page 5-6).</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Validator</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>All bugs raised by users following the testing phase have been fixed</li>
<li>There is a new feature to allow the bulk-uploading of files</li>
<li>Users can now receive validation reports via email.</li>
</ul>
<p>The IATI Technical Team has worked with suppliers <a href="https://zimmerman.team/">Zimmerman</a> (who continue to host the new IATI Datastore) and <a href="https://data4development.nl/en/">Data4Development</a> (developers of the new IATI Validator, now hosted by the IATI Secretariat) to implement changes to both products.</p>
<h3>Important: Deprecation of old Datastore and Public Validator - 22 March 2021</h3>
<p>As previously announced, the new IATI Datastore and Validator replace the old Datastore CSV Query Builder, API and Public Validator. These older versions will be deprecated on Monday 22 March 2021 and after this date, users will no longer be able to access these services.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>Old Datastore API:</strong>  Between now and 22 March 2021 users can choose to  <em>either</em>  use existing API calls to return data from the old Datastore,  <em>or</em>  use a Redirect version from the Old Datastore to the new Datastore. Redirects can be tested by replacing “<a href="http://datastore.iatistandard.org">datastore.iatistandard.org</a>” in previous queries with “<a href="http://datastoreredirect.iatistandard.org">datastoreredirect.iatistandard.org</a>.” By using this version, existing API calls will be redirected and return data from the new Datastore. After 22 March 2021, the old Datastore will be deprecated and  <strong>all</strong>  queries to the Old Datastore will automatically be redirected to corresponding queries on the new Datastore.</li>
</ul>
<p>For any questions or support to transition to using the new Datastore and Validator, please email the IATI Secretariat: <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a>.</p>
<h3>Upcoming work</h3>
<p>IATI’s Secretariat is committed to maintaining and updating all IATI digital products to meet users’ needs. Some examples of planned work include:</p>
<p><strong>Datastore:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Enable transaction and activity level data to be output from a single query</li>
<li>Enable output of normalised USD values for transactions, regardless of published currency</li>
<li>Enable output of validation results.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Validator:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Key priority post-launch is working proactively with publishers in fixing data errors and improving their data quality.</li>
</ul>
<p>To provide feedback on either of these two projects, please raise an issue on Github: <a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-team/iati.cloud/issues">IATI Datastore</a> <a href="https://github.com/IATI/IATI-Validator-Web">Validator</a> or email <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a></p>
            <p><small>8 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iatis-datastore-and-validator-tools-launched/2021">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iatis-datastore-and-validator-tools-launched/2021</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 10:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-2021</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iatis-datastore-and-validator-tools-launched/2021.rss">IATI&#39;s Datastore and Validator Tools launched</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>IATI Publishing Guidance Pages- How to Suggest Changes - input by 12 October</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The IATI Technical Team has written process guidance on how to make changes to the <a href="https://iatistandard.org/en/guidance/standard-guidance/">IATI Standard Publishing Guidance pages</a>. Please note that this is a new process and we will monitoring how it works and will revisit this after one year of application. On suggested use of platform, such as Github and Discuss, we will of course also look into how we can use the new IATI community platform once set in place.</p>
<p>In the process of writing this guidance, we looked at <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1xjlAneqgewZvHh6_hwuQ98hbjxRcA2IUqOTJiNGcOf8/edit#heading=h.irnq91ktnkzz">Open Contracting Guidance</a> to see how others have approached similar process; we also discussed this with IATI Governing Board Focal Points Melinda Cuzner and Leo Stolk.</p>
<p>We would like to share the <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1mfbj1HlGavi1AU0nJSJVwxx5_j0lXB8dwV8EiSURvWw/edit#heading=h.s5ha71xbo7cp">IATI Standard Publishing Guidance - How to Make Changes document</a> with you in advance to make sure it is clear and straightforward. Please respond to this thread by  <strong>Friday 2 October</strong>  if you have clarification comments and we will make sure we address them. We will then publish this on our main website and link to it from the IATI Publishing Guidance pages as well.</p>
            <p><small>9 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-publishing-guidance-pages-how-to-suggest-changes-input-by-12-october/2020">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-publishing-guidance-pages-how-to-suggest-changes-input-by-12-october/2020</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 08:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-2020</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-publishing-guidance-pages-how-to-suggest-changes-input-by-12-october/2020.rss">IATI Publishing Guidance Pages- How to Suggest Changes - input by 12 October</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Datastore Project Update: August 2020</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Zimmerman and the IATI Secretariat are pleased to provide an update on the progress of the IATI Datastore project.</p>
<p>Over the last few months we have worked intensively to make a huge number of improvements to the tool, in response to community feedback during the testing phase, and to satisfy remaining requirements from the TOR. We’ve fixed bugs and added the required enhancements that enable the tool to be as robust and dependable as possible. We are working towards a release date of 22nd September.</p>
<p><strong>What work has been completed?</strong></p>
<p>A non-exhaustive list of these items include:</p>
<p>Bug fixes:</p>
<ul>
<li>0.00 values not being output</li>
<li>‘Default’ elements being farmed to transactions</li>
<li>Location output not matching published data</li>
<li>Multiple description types not output</li>
</ul>
<p>Functional Additions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Validator Integration</li>
<li>Schema-valid XML output</li>
<li>Several additional filters</li>
<li>Streamlined parsing process</li>
<li>Output CSV columns in Schema order</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Remaining Requirements and official launch</strong></p>
<p>As existing users will know, all items mentioned above have been implemented and are available to use now.</p>
<p>The only remaining requirement for the product to be fully launched is for sector and recipient-country expansion functionality to be added to the csv output. Sector and recipient-country expansion allows, if required by the user, the ability to repeat each activity or transaction (depending on the row-output choice) over multiple rows, for each sector or recipient-country that is reported.</p>
<p>The core functionality is already available on the tool, but the Zimmerman team is now working to make this available for all filters, and ensuring that all fields can be returned, as required.</p>
<p>Once the work on the sector and recipient-country expansion feature is completed, the tool will be ready for launch. The purpose of the launch is to actively promote the use of the IATI Datastore both to existing and new IATI stakeholders within the international development and humanitarian sectors. A comprehensive User Guide for the Query Builder will also be published at the time of launch.</p>
<p><strong>Redirects</strong></p>
<p>As mentioned on a previous <a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-datastore-redirects-testing/1970">Discuss post</a>, an important requirement is that queries that are made to the ‘old’ IATI Datastore API are redirected to the new one, with the equivalent query parameters used. This will ensure that any regular queries that utilise the existing tool can continue to return corresponding data from the new tool.</p>
<p>The timeline for deprecating the old Datastore and implementing the redirects is as follows:</p>
<p>From New Datastore communications Launch until 6 months after:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<a href="http://datastore.iatistandard.org/query/">Old Datastore</a> remains live, as is.</li>
<li>“Redirect version” of Old Datastore is also available for use. The “Redirect version” of the Old Datastore will provide users with the corresponding query to the New Datastore. This should help with any migrations before the Old Datastore is deprecated</li>
</ul>
<p>6 months after Datastore official launch</p>
<ul>
<li>Old Datastore is deprecated and no longer available</li>
<li>“Redirect version” of Old Datastore is deprecated and no longer available</li>
<li>Any queries to the Old Datastore <strong>automatically</strong> redirect to a corresponding query on the new Datastore.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Post Launch Requirements</strong></p>
<p>Following the launch, we will continue to work on implementing the following requirements previously identified and keep the Community updated as to when these will be released .</p>
<ul>
<li>Allow elements that can be returned at either transaction or activity level to be returned within the same query - <a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/iati.cloud/issues/2081">#2081</a>
</li>
<li>Add aggregated transaction data to the activity output - <a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/iati.cloud/issues/2025">#2025</a>
</li>
<li>Allow the user to choose between basic, complete, or custom csv output - <a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/iati.cloud/issues/2295">#2295</a>
</li>
<li>Normalise transaction values to USD - <a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/iati.cloud/issues/2219">#2219</a>
</li>
<li>Enable return of Validation results from the Datastore - <a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/iati.cloud/issues/2296">#2296</a>
</li>
</ul>
<p>As with all of our services, the IATI Secretariat will continue to monitor and respond to user needs with any necessary updates in the future, and will undertake consultations with the wider IATI Community about potential changes to the datastore and validator integration, including on topics currently under review <a href="https://eur03.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdiscuss.iatistandard.org%2Ft%2Fiati-datastore-what-data-should-go-in%2F1631%2F60&amp;data=02%7C01%7Cannelise.parr%40undp.org%7C265f99d70f7b41a1a25108d83882e69e%7Cb3e5db5e2944483799f57488ace54319%7C0%7C0%7C637321482149473130&amp;sdata=97y7HQbUV5a4JEbPHjcLUVXIWFD%2FqGIAodm4z1rJvI0%3D&amp;reserved=0">on Discuss.</a></p>
<p><strong>Get in touch</strong></p>
<p>As ever, if you have further questions for the IATI Secretariat and Zimmerman, do post them here or email <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a>.</p>
<p>Best wishes,<br>
IATI Secretariat &amp; Zimmerman Team</p>
            <p><small>4 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/datastore-project-update-august-2020/2000">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/datastore-project-update-august-2020/2000</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 10:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-2000</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/datastore-project-update-august-2020/2000.rss">Datastore Project Update: August 2020</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Moving IATI Standard content from IATI reference site to main IATI website</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This post provides an update on the work to migrate IATI Standard content from IATI’s old Reference site (now available <a href="http://archivereference.iatistandard.org/">here</a>) to <a href="http://iatistandard.org">iatistandard.org</a> as announced in our <a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/technical-notice-moving-iati-standard-content-from-iati-reference-site-to-main-iati-website/1897/14">previous posts</a>. Many thanks to all the feedback from the community on this project.</p>
<p><strong>What changes have been made?</strong></p>
<p>IATI’s website has been updated to include information on the rules and guidance of the IATI Standard. Content previously held on IATI’s old <a href="http://archivereference.iatistandard.org/">Reference site</a> has been added to <a href="http://iatistandard.org">iatistandard.org</a>, ensuring all information about the IATI Standard can be easily accessed in one place.</p>
<p><strong>All IATI Standard information now on <a href="http://iatistandard.org">iatistandard.org</a></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Technical documentation on all components of the IATI Standard (elements, attributes, rulesets, upgrades etc.) can be found in the <a href="http://iatistandard.org/en/iati-standard/">IATI Standard section</a> of this website. Do note, as the IATI Standard version 1 was deprecated in 2019, all version 1 pages are kept as an archive within this section.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>All guidance material (including setting up IATI accounts, how to publish data, Standard guidance and developer documentation) can be found in the <a href="https://iatistandard.org/en/guidance/">Guidance and Support</a> section of the website.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Old IATI Reference site</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The old IATI Reference site has been archived and will be turned off in 6 months time on 3 February 2020.</li>
<li>However, from today users who access old links to the IATI Reference site, will be redirected to the new pages on <a href="http://iatistandard.org">iatistandard.org</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Users should note that no information on the IATI Standard that has been migrated from the old IATI Reference site has changed, however it has been reordered and re-structured on <a href="http://iatistandard.org">iatistandard.org</a>. Updates have been made to content in the Guidance section of <a href="http://iatistandard.org">iatistandard.org</a>, following consultations with the community. These changes will make it easier and more streamlined for publishers and data users to find and understand information about the IATI Standard.</p>
<p><strong>Additional Technical changes: IATI - GitHub</strong></p>
<p>There have also been a few behind-the-scenes changes on <a href="https://github.com/IATI">IATI-GitHub</a> to provide more flexibility in how the Secretariat can use and display IATI Standard content.</p>
<p><strong>Changes:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>From IATI/Extra-Documentation we have moved:</p>
<ul>
<li>The updated overview pages to the IATI/Guidance repository</li>
<li>The codelist-api.rst page now sits within IATI/Developer-Documentation</li>
<li>The codelist-management.rst page sits within IATI/Upgrades</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>From IATI/Guidance we have moved:</p>
<ul>
<li>The old datastore documentation to the IATI/Developer Documentation repository</li>
<li>The old introduction pages have been archived as these are now contained within Wagtail CMS as per the first website launch</li>
<li>The IATI upgrade pages to the IATI/Upgrades repository.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>These changes provide the Technical Team with the required level of version control for each page type. For example, we only need one copy of each IATI standard upgrade page. These pages do not differ between the IATI versions.</p>
<p><strong>Next steps</strong></p>
<p>In the coming months we will continue to undertake formatting fixes and optimisations on <a href="http://iatistandard.org">iatistandard.org</a>. These will happen both on the website and behind the scenes.</p>
<p>We’re committed to listening to any feedback so please email any questions about these changes to <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a>.</p>
            <p><small>33 posts - 7 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/moving-iati-standard-content-from-iati-reference-site-to-main-iati-website/1987">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/moving-iati-standard-content-from-iati-reference-site-to-main-iati-website/1987</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 14:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1987</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/moving-iati-standard-content-from-iati-reference-site-to-main-iati-website/1987.rss">Moving IATI Standard content from IATI reference site to main IATI website</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>IATI website work: 09/07/2020</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Technical notice: <a href="https://t.co/fRtC1mYbZM?amp=1">http://iatistandard.org </a> will be undergoing further updates from 2pm today (UK time) and users may experiences issues with using the site over the next 24 hours. For any questions or help email IATI’s Technical Team at <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a>.</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-website-work-09-07-2020/1986">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-website-work-09-07-2020/1986</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 12:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1986</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-website-work-09-07-2020/1986.rss">IATI website work: 09/07/2020</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>IATI website work 02/07/2020</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Technical notice: <a href="https://t.co/fRtC1mYbZM?amp=1">http://iatistandard.org</a> will be ungoing updates from 2pm today (UK time) and users may experiences issues with using the site over the next 24 hours. For any questions or help email IATI’s Technical Team at <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a>.</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-website-work-02-07-2020/1981">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-website-work-02-07-2020/1981</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 12:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1981</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-website-work-02-07-2020/1981.rss">IATI website work 02/07/2020</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>IATI Data Removal Guidance: input by 26 June</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The IATI Technical Team has written guidance for data owners to explain the process for removing data published to the IATI Standard.</p>
<p>In the process of writing this guidance, we looked at 360 Giving’s data takedown policy to see how others have approached similar guidance on data removal; we also discussed this with the suppliers of the tools referenced in the document, as well as IATI Governing Board Focal Points Melinda Cuzner and Leo Stolk.</p>
<p>We would like to share the <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1s6imId9bBwGiY2nEnjM8zwf4BpIBOfxk7JJt8WKIC7Y/edit#heading=h.8vz5yjg6bj9f">IATI data removal guidance</a> with you in advance to make sure it is clear and straightforward. Please respond to this thread by <strong>Friday 26 June</strong> if you have clarification comments and we will make sure we address them. We will then publish this on our main website and link to it from the relevant publisher guidance pages as well.</p>
            <p><small>6 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-data-removal-guidance-input-by-26-june/1973">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-data-removal-guidance-input-by-26-june/1973</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 16:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1973</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-data-removal-guidance-input-by-26-june/1973.rss">IATI Data Removal Guidance: input by 26 June</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>IATI Datastore: Redirects Testing</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>As you are aware, the IATI Tech Team has been working on delivering the new<a href="https://iatidatastore.iatistandard.org/"> IATI Datastore</a>. The tool is currently in a ‘pre-launch’ phase and will be fully released in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>As per previous project updates, an important requirement is that queries that are made to the ‘old’ IATI Datastore API are redirected to the new one, with the equivalent query parameters used. This will ensure that any regular queries that utilise the existing tool can continue to return corresponding data from the new tool.</p>
<p><strong>Please test Datastore API redirects</strong></p>
<p>We have now implemented these redirects on a test version of the old Datastore and as a user of the existing tool, we would welcome your input in this testing phase, as we are aware that your organisation makes (or has previously made) regular queries to the old Datastore.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>To test the redirect functionality, use a regular API query and substitute “<a href="http://datastore.iatistandard.org/api/1/access/activity.csv?reporting-org=GB-COH-07291220&amp;stream=True">http://datastore.iatistandard.org</a>” for “<a href="http://104.248.175.88">http://104.248.175.88</a>”.For example, to return all activities where Somalia is reported as a recipient-country, you could use this URL:<br>
<a href="http://datastore.iatistandard.org/api/1/access/activity.xml?recipient-country=SO&amp;stream=true">http://datastore.iatistandard.org/api/1/access/activity.xml?recipient-country=SO&amp;stream=true</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>To test the redirect, you should use the URL:<br>
<a href="http://104.248.175.88/">http://104.248.175.88</a><a href="http://104.248.175.88/api/1/access/activity.xml?recipient-country=SO&amp;stream=true">/api/1/access/activity.xml?recipient-country=SO&amp;stream=true</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Instead of immediately returning the results, you will be presented with the redirected query for the new Datastore. You should then run this query to check that the results correspond with your original regular query. Once the tool is fully launched, the redirected query will be run automatically, rather than just the URL being displayed.</p>
<p>It is important to note that we <strong>do not</strong> expect the number of activities that are returned to be the same when an equivalent query is made using the two different tools. The new Datastore does not import data that is published at version 1 of the IATI Standard or datasets that do not conform to the IATI Schema.</p>
<p><strong>Provide feedback by 15 June</strong></p>
<p>Rather, we would appreciate your feedback on whether the parameters translate correctly, and that the data that is returned corresponds with these parameters as expected. Please provide your feedback by Friday 15th June.</p>
<p>If you have any questions, please do not hesitate to ask.</p>
<p>Many thanks,<br>
IATI Tech Team</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-datastore-redirects-testing/1970">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-datastore-redirects-testing/1970</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 15:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1970</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-datastore-redirects-testing/1970.rss">IATI Datastore: Redirects Testing</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Submit bid for IATI Data Use Fund</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The International Aid Transparency Initiative (IATI) is inviting proposals to deliver an <a href="https://procurement-notices.undp.org/view_notice.cfm?notice_id=66129">inventory of IATI training materials and data use tools</a> under IATI’s Data Use Fund (deadline 19 June).</p>
<p>UNDP/IATI is seeking to contract a service provider to create an inventory of existing training materials on using IATI data and conduct a gap analysis to understand what additional resources are required to support data users.</p>
<p>Interested and qualified service providers are encouraged to submit their bid according the <a href="https://procurement-notices.undp.org/view_notice.cfm?notice_id=66129">Requests for Proposals (RfPs)</a> by  <strong>Friday 19 June 2020</strong>.</p>
<p>See full information on the RFP on the <a href="https://procurement-notices.undp.org/view_notice.cfm?notice_id=66129">UNDP Procurement website</a>. For more information please contact Anna Whitson, IATI Outreach and Partnerships Specialist at <a href="mailto:anna.whitson@undp.org">anna.whitson@undp.org</a>.</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/submit-bid-for-iati-data-use-fund/1966">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/submit-bid-for-iati-data-use-fund/1966</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 15:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1966</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/submit-bid-for-iati-data-use-fund/1966.rss">Submit bid for IATI Data Use Fund</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>IATI Strategic Plan Results Framework Survey - for Data Users</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>In line with its <a href="https://eur03.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fiatistandard.org%2Fen%2Fgovernance%2Fiati-strategic-plan-2020-2025%2F&amp;data=02%7C01%7Canna.whitson%40undp.org%7C277cbae85d6b45c1909d08d7e6e1d827%7Cb3e5db5e2944483799f57488ace54319%7C0%7C0%7C637231729981460839&amp;sdata=4jZGulw3DTO0XLhBR5gSQor%2F5r1rUsewKFxGb%2F6b1TM%3D&amp;reserved=0">2020-2025 Strategic Plan</a>, the International Aid Transparency Initiative (IATI) is reinforcing efforts to track the quality and use of IATI data and the strength of IATI community engagement.</p>
<p>As such, a Results Framework for the Strategic Plan is under development, which will ensure that decisions on the future of IATI are based on real progress, and that this progress can be tracked and shared. To establish baselines for the Results Framework, IATI is inviting all colleagues who <strong>accessed or used IATI data in 2019 to complete this</strong> <a href="https://bit.ly/IATIdatausesurvey">brief survey</a> by <strong>15 May</strong>.</p>
<h3><a href="https://bit.ly/IATIdatausesurvey"> <strong>Take IATI Strategic Plan Results Framework Survey - for Data Users</strong> </a></h3>
<p>The survey should take approximately five minutes to complete and is open to any person who accessed or used IATI data in 2019. <strong>Please do not complete this survey if you have already responded to the Members / Publishers survey.</strong>  Please note that your responses will not be shared beyond the IATI Secretariat, other than in aggregated analysis. Kindly direct any questions on the survey to Secretariat member Anna Whitson at <a href="mailto:anna.whitson@undp.org">anna.whitson@undp.org</a>.</p>
<p>Your input will be vital to IATI’s efforts to track progress and hold ourselves accountable to our mandate of improving the transparency of development and humanitarian resources and their results to address poverty and crises.</p>
<p>We thank you in advance for participating!</p>
<p>Best,<br>
The IATI Secretariat</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-strategic-plan-results-framework-survey-for-data-users/1941">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-strategic-plan-results-framework-survey-for-data-users/1941</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 10:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1941</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-strategic-plan-results-framework-survey-for-data-users/1941.rss">IATI Strategic Plan Results Framework Survey - for Data Users</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Python3 Upgrade: Proposed Publishing Statistics Changes (comment by 15th April)</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>As outlined in a previous <a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/python-2-x-deprecation-notice/1725/4">Discuss post</a>, the Technical Team has been working towards upgrading the programming language that is used across a number of IATI tools from Python 2.x to Python 3.x</p>
<p>One of the tools that is undergoing upgrade work is IATI’s <a href="http://publishingstats.iatistandard.org/">Publishing Statistics site.</a></p>
<p>Some of the functionality changes between Python2 and Python3 have led to some scores in the Publishing Statistics pages altering slightly. These changes - and how we propose to handle them - are summarised below:</p>
<p><strong>Change to <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/10825926/python-3-x-rounding-behavior">‘Bankers’ Rounding’</a></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>In Python2, x.5 numbers are rounded away from 0. E.g. 75.5 rounds to 76, 76.5 rounds to 77.</li>
<li>In Python3, x.5 numbers are rounded to the nearest even integer. Therefore 75.5 still rounds to 76, but 76.5 would also round to 76.</li>
<li>This means in Python3 that two publishers with a score that is a whole integer different in an initial calculation (e.g. 75.5 and 76.5) could be assigned the same score - 76 in this case.</li>
<li>The Technical Team proposes that we amend the code so that the Python2 functionality is replicated (while still upgrading the language itself to Python3), so that those two publishers would continue to score 76 and 77, respectively.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Change to <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/19507808/python3-integer-division">integer division</a> functionality</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>In Python2, an integer divided by another integer, yields an integer. E.g. (2 / 3) * 100 = 66%</li>
<li>In Python3, an integer divided by another integer, yields a ‘float’. E.g. (2 / 3) * 100 = 66.66%</li>
<li>The Technical Team proposes that the core Python3 functionality is retained. Therefore where an initial calculation of 66.66 is currently output as 66, this will change to the value being output as 67.</li>
</ul>
<p>The only material difference to the metrics (as a result of the integer division change)  is that some values in the Publishing Statistics  calculations will be <strong>one unit higher</strong> than they currently are. Therefore, <strong>no publisher will be penalised by the changes that we propose.</strong></p>
<p>We welcome the community’s thoughts on this before proceeding with the amendments and deploying to the live Publisher Statistics site. Please provide your input by <strong>Wednesday 15th April.</strong> The upgrade will be implemented following this if there are no objections.</p>
<p>Many thanks,<br>
IATI Tech Team</p>
            <p><small>7 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/python3-upgrade-proposed-publishing-statistics-changes-comment-by-15th-april/1924">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/python3-upgrade-proposed-publishing-statistics-changes-comment-by-15th-april/1924</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 11:14:50 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1924</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/python3-upgrade-proposed-publishing-statistics-changes-comment-by-15th-april/1924.rss">Python3 Upgrade: Proposed Publishing Statistics Changes (comment by 15th April)</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Service Desk Holiday Closure</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi all,</p>
<p>Please note that the IATI Service Desk will be closed between 23rd December and 1st January (inclusive) and will be open again as normal on 2nd January.</p>
<p>We will respond to any queries received over the closure period as soon as possible once it is reopened.</p>
<p>We hope everyone has a wonderful holiday period!</p>
<p>Many thanks,<br>
The Tech Team <img src="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/images/emoji/twitter/christmas_tree.png?v=9" title=":christmas_tree:" class="emoji" alt=":christmas_tree:"><img src="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/images/emoji/twitter/star.png?v=9" title=":star:" class="emoji" alt=":star:"><img src="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/images/emoji/twitter/gift.png?v=9" title=":gift:" class="emoji" alt=":gift:"><img src="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/images/emoji/twitter/snowman.png?v=9" title=":snowman:" class="emoji" alt=":snowman:"></p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/service-desk-holiday-closure/1884">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/service-desk-holiday-closure/1884</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 12:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1884</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/service-desk-holiday-closure/1884.rss">Service Desk Holiday Closure</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Datastore &amp; Query Builder: Project Update</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Earlier this year, in August and October respectively, the IATI Technical Team and Zimmerman &amp; Zimmerman released the <a href="https://datastore.iati.cloud/" rel="nofollow noopener">new IATI Datastore</a> and <a href="https://datastore.iati.cloud/querybuilder/core-filters" rel="nofollow noopener">Query Builder</a> for testing.</p>
<p>We would like to thank members of the IATI community who engaged in testing both the API and Query Builder. Your feedback has proved invaluable in discovering bugs and raising potential improvements for the products.</p>
<p>A number of bug fixes and functionality improvements have already been implemented based on the public feedback, including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ensuring that the default XML output from the Activity endpoint complies with the IATI Standard Schema (<a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/iati.cloud/issues/1638" rel="nofollow noopener">#1638</a>)</li>
<li>Transactions and Results have been added to the Activities endpoint output (<a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/iati.cloud/issues/1628" rel="nofollow noopener">#1628</a>, <a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/iati.cloud/issues/1677" rel="nofollow noopener">#1677</a>)</li>
<li>Allow for full, unpaginated results via the Solr function (<a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/iati.cloud/issues/1520" rel="nofollow noopener">#1520</a>)</li>
<li>Moving documentation to internal server to streamline loading (<a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/iati.cloud/issues/1676" rel="nofollow noopener">#1676</a>)</li>
<li>Flatten CSV output so that there so only data is returned (no JSON within cells) (<a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/iati.cloud/issues/1817" rel="nofollow noopener">#1817</a>)</li>
<li>Ensure that “0.00” values in published data are not replaced by “ ” in DS results (<a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/iati.cloud/issues/1707" rel="nofollow noopener">#1707</a>)</li>
</ul>
<p>For a full list of issues that have been raised, please see the <a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/iati.cloud/projects/5" rel="nofollow noopener">GitHub project board</a>.</p>
<p><strong>What’s next?</strong></p>
<p>The project team are now evaluating which outstanding bug fixes and functionality enhancements are required to be implemented before the product can be fully launched.</p>
<p>Once work on these items has been completed, a launch date will be set. The following requirements are included:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ensure that parameter names are consistent with their corresponding IATI Standard element (<a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/iati.cloud/issues/1643" rel="nofollow noopener">#1643</a>)</li>
<li>Ensure that equivalent data is simultaneously available between the standard API and Solr functions (<a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/iati.cloud/issues/1841" rel="nofollow noopener">#1841</a>)</li>
<li>Ensure that data is parsed successfully when a vocabulary is not present, in instances where a vocabulary is assumed if not provided (<a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/iati.cloud/issues/1713" rel="nofollow noopener">#1713</a>)</li>
<li>Implement redirects from queries to ‘old’ DS to equivalent queries on the new DS (<a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/iati.cloud/issues/1962" rel="nofollow noopener">#1962</a>)</li>
</ul>
<p>We continue to welcome further input on the project at this time, as there are also a number of backlogged items that the team will work on beyond the date of the official launch.</p>
<p><strong>Old Datastore API and Query Builder</strong></p>
<p>As has been previously mentioned , the ‘old’ Datastore API and Query Builder will be phased out six months after the full launch of the new Datastore API and Query Builder. We do not recommend that users migrate any tools which currently utilise the old Datastore until the new Datastore has been officially launched.</p>
<p><strong>Please continue to check IATI Discuss for future updates in regard to a date for the official, full launch of the new IATI Datastore.</strong></p>
            <p><small>7 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/datastore-query-builder-project-update/1877">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/datastore-query-builder-project-update/1877</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 16:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1877</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/datastore-query-builder-project-update/1877.rss">Datastore &amp; Query Builder: Project Update</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>New IATI Validator launched for public testing</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The IATI Technical Team and Data4Development are very pleased to launch the new IATI Validator for a month of testing between <strong>12 November and 11 December.</strong></p>
<p><strong>About the new IATI Validator</strong></p>
<p>The new IATI Validator will replace the existing <a href="http://validator.iatistandard.org/" rel="nofollow noopener">IATI public validator</a> to offer a more robust service. The tool checks data against all rules and guidance (musts &amp; shoulds) in the IATI Standard. The tool aims to improve the quality of IATI data to ensure it is accessible and useful to anyone working with data on development and humanitarian resources and results.</p>
<p>Access the new <a href="https://test-validator.iatistandard.org/" rel="nofollow noopener">IATI Validator</a> now.</p>
<p><strong>Please help test the new IATI Validator</strong></p>
<p>To test the new IATI Validator, please check the quality of IATI data files and provide feedback on your experience. Specifically:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>publishers are requested to <a href="https://test-validator.iatistandard.org/validate" rel="nofollow noopener">check their own data</a> by uploading unpublished IATI files to understand if the content complies with the IATI Standard;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>publishers should also test the <a href="https://test-validator.iatistandard.org/organisations" rel="nofollow noopener">Public Data Viewer</a> to check the IATI files that they have already published;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>all data users can test the <a href="https://test-validator.iatistandard.org/organisations" rel="nofollow noopener">Public Data Viewer</a> to find information about the quality of any publishers’ IATI data files.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Please provide your feedback by using the <a href="https://test-validator.iatistandard.org/" rel="nofollow noopener">Validator Feedback form on the tool</a> or raise issues on <a href="https://github.com/data4development/IATI-data-validator/issues/new/choose" rel="nofollow noopener">Github</a>. Users who are unable to access Github or use the Validator Feedback form are welcome to share their feedback by emailing <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Provide feedback on specific issues</strong></p>
<p>To help the Technical Team and Data4development sort through feedback efficiently, please provide separate comments/issues on:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Reporting a bug (where something is not working e.g. broken links)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Requesting a feature/enhancement e.g. improvement in visual design</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Questions/comments on how the rules and guidance are being checked by the new IATI Validator</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Support using the new IATI Validator</strong></p>
<p>Users can access the following support to use the new tool:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1oOdq4keBXz6Ahmn3UiFYitSiQl3p7xDK51w_VWYVVPw/edit?usp=sharing" rel="nofollow noopener">Q&amp;A: New IATI Validator (testing phase)</a></li>
<li>IATI Standard Guidance documents, signposted to by the IATI Validator</li>
<li>IATI Technical Team helpdesk <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a>.</li>
<li>Webinar on how to use the IATI Validator - Wednesday 27 November 2019, 3pm UK time (registration details to follow shortly). More webinars will be scheduled to meet demand, if required.</li>
<li>One-to-one calls with the Technical Team if required</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>More checks, more errors - but no cause for alarm</strong></p>
<p>The new IATI Validator checks data against all rules of the IATI Standard. We anticipate that by using the new tool, publishers will discover many more errors than were previously picked up with the old tool. Therefore, they may have many corrections to make to their data. These may take some time to address, and it is important to keep in mind that publishers are not expected to correct their data immediately. Using the tool will help publishers understand where there are errors and make appropriate corrections to ensure their data is of the highest quality.</p>
<p>Do contact the <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">IATI Technical Team</a> for help or questions about making corrections to your data.</p>
<p><strong>Tech note: where to find further information on Validator checks?</strong></p>
<p>The new IATI Validator runs checks against version 2 of the Schema and Rulesets of the IATI Standard. Full information about the IATI Schema can be found on <a href="http://reference.iatistandard.org/203/schema/" rel="nofollow noopener">IATI’s Reference site</a>. To view the most up-to-date information about IATI’s Rulesets please refer to <a href="https://github.com/data4development/IATI-Rulesets" rel="nofollow noopener">Data4Developement’s IATI Ruleset repository</a>.</p>
<p>For more technical information, please see <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1oOdq4keBXz6Ahmn3UiFYitSiQl3p7xDK51w_VWYVVPw/edit?usp=sharing" rel="nofollow noopener">Q&amp;A: New IATI Validator (testing phase)</a>.</p>
<p><strong>What will happen after the Validator testing phase?</strong></p>
<p>After the testing period is over, the Technical Team will review all feedback and suggestions for changes that were not addressed during the testing phase. The Team will post a summary of responses on IATI Discuss and let users know how they will be addressed in the future, and plans for phasing out the older <a href="http://validator.iatistandard.org/" rel="nofollow noopener">IATI public validator</a>.</p>
<p>Thanks in advance to IATI’s dedicated community who are able to support the testing phase of the new IATI Validator. For any questions please email: <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a>.</p>
            <p><small>8 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/new-iati-validator-launched-for-public-testing/1870">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/new-iati-validator-launched-for-public-testing/1870</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 10:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1870</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/new-iati-validator-launched-for-public-testing/1870.rss">New IATI Validator launched for public testing</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Register for the IATI SDG Publishing Webinars- 30 October &amp; 6 November</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>In September IATI published guidance on <a href="https://drive.google.com/open?id=1Xg8OwtFATaD5iMFFCrJyOibw7uQX_Dd8" rel="nofollow noopener">how to use the IATI Standard for publishing and using data on the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs)</a>.</p>
<p>The guidance is targeted at publishers who already have a knowledge of IATI and are looking to increase the usability of their data. It provides instructions on how to align activities with the SDG Goals, Targets and Indicators.</p>
<p>We’re holding two webinars to take publishers through the guidance, explain in more detail how to add SDG data into their IATI files, and answer any questions. The webinars will focus on:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Demonstrating how to report SDG Goals &amp; Targets using the  element.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Demonstrating how to report SDG Indicators as part of the  element.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Participants should read the IATI SDG Guidance: <a href="https://iatistandard.org/documents/836/Publishing_SDG_data_using_the_IATI_Standard_September_2019.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener">Publishing SDG data using the IATI Standard</a> in advance. It would also be helpful to send in questions ahead of the webinar via the Zoom registration links below or by emailing <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Registration for the webinars is now open:</strong></p>
<p><strong>30 October 2019 3.30pm (UK) - Goals &amp; Targets</strong></p>
<p>Register here:<a href="https://zoom.us/meeting/register/c2e0e15b4d085ede8c34be5db4a05ad8" rel="nofollow noopener"> https://zoom.us/meeting/register/c2e0e15b4d085ede8c34be5db4a05ad8</a></p>
<p><strong>06 November 2019 3.30pm (UK) - Indicators</strong></p>
<p>Register here: <a href="https://zoom.us/meeting/register/dd4bb8c4bf0b2f9c7510d14dfea9e911" rel="nofollow noopener"> https://zoom.us/meeting/register/dd4bb8c4bf0b2f9c7510d14dfea9e911</a></p>
<p>If you are unable to attend these sessions, we will make recordings available.</p>
<p>Please note that these webinars will focus upon publishing SDG data in IATI. We are hoping to hold further webinars around accessing and using IATI SDG data next year. If you are interested in being involved in these webinars, please let us know by emailing us at: <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a>.</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/register-for-the-iati-sdg-publishing-webinars-30-october-6-november/1863">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/register-for-the-iati-sdg-publishing-webinars-30-october-6-november/1863</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 09:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1863</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/register-for-the-iati-sdg-publishing-webinars-30-october-6-november/1863.rss">Register for the IATI SDG Publishing Webinars- 30 October &amp; 6 November</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>IATI Data Use Fund: RfP for researching feedback mechanisms extended</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The deadline for the RfP on researching feedback mechanisms has been extended to the <strong>25th October.</strong></p>
<p>Please see the following message from the IATI Secretariat:</p>
<hr>
<p>Under the auspices of the IATI Data Use Task Force, UNDP is seeking to contract a service provider who has the capacity to conduct extensive research on options for a web-based feedback mechanism between IATI data users and publishers. The aim of this project is to provide recommendations to IATI on how a feedback mechanism could be designed and implemented with the ultimate goal of improving the quality of data published to IATI.</p>
<p>The service provider is expected to develop the concept and conduct the research (in coordination with the IATI Coordinator who is based at UNDP), document research results and provide UNDP with a final report that contains detailed information and recommendations for a web-based feedback loop.</p>
<p><strong>We would therefore appreciate if you could circulate this <a href="http://procurement-notices.undp.org/view_file.cfm?doc_id=192002" rel="nofollow noopener">Request for Proposal</a>, which contains additional relevant information, among any firms or vendors who might be interested.</strong></p>
<p>The deadline for receipt of proposals has been extended to  <strong>Friday, 25 October</strong> and bids should be submitted through the official <a href="http://procurement-notices.undp.org/view_notice.cfm?notice_id=59553" rel="nofollow noopener">UNDP procurement portal</a>. Any questions on the contents of the RfP or the process of submitting a bid can be directed to Anna Whitson at <a href="mailto:anna.whitson@undp.org">anna.whitson@undp.org</a>.</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-data-use-fund-rfp-for-researching-feedback-mechanisms-extended/1861">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-data-use-fund-rfp-for-researching-feedback-mechanisms-extended/1861</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 16:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1861</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-data-use-fund-rfp-for-researching-feedback-mechanisms-extended/1861.rss">IATI Data Use Fund: RfP for researching feedback mechanisms extended</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>IATI Datastore&#39;s new Query Builder is launched for testing</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>IATI has launched a new online tool offering easy access to development and humanitarian data published according to the IATI Standard. This complements IATI’s existing suite of online tools for data users such as <a href="http://www.d-portal.org/ctrack.html#view=search">d-portal.org</a>, and allows for much more detailed queries and searches of published data than previously possible.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://iatidatastore.iatistandard.org/">Try the new IATI Datastore Query Builder now.</a></strong></p>
<p><strong>About the IATI Datastore Query Builder</strong></p>
<p>The new <a href="https://iatidatastore.iatistandard.org/">IATI Datastore Query Builder</a> allows complex searches of spending and activities published according to the IATI Standard by donor governments, development finance institutions, UN agencies, non-governmental organisations, foundations and private sector organisations. The Query Builder uses data available from IATI’s <a href="https://iatistandard.org/en/news/new-iati-datastore-api-launched-for-testing/">new Datastore</a>, released in September 2019.</p>
<p>By entering search parameters into the online tool, users can access development and humanitarian activities across 32 different fields (elements) of the IATI Standard. For example, users can filter by transaction type, activity status, or whether an activity is specifically addressing a humanitarian crisis.</p>
<p><strong><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/ILcVcW4a2AjY5el7-Q4TamJZM_9f1yLBlxtNE7qkqeajh6CWkKZ_GKRBcgVdgjmnxwXVI6Q1XE6oNTPlPcdYFcPh11ZWJqG2lRMbP57B4VL0dxaa1RKkVBPqDcTPXOfymYIfrZWy" title=""><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/ILcVcW4a2AjY5el7-Q4TamJZM_9f1yLBlxtNE7qkqeajh6CWkKZ_GKRBcgVdgjmnxwXVI6Q1XE6oNTPlPcdYFcPh11ZWJqG2lRMbP57B4VL0dxaa1RKkVBPqDcTPXOfymYIfrZWy" alt="" width="500" height="418"><div class="meta"><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename"></span><span class="informations">1097×919</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg></div></a></div></strong></p>
<p><strong>Improved access to IATI data</strong></p>
<p>The new IATI Datastore Query Builder provides access to data that complies with the most up-to-date rules of the IATI Standard. The new tool will:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Provide data from organisations that have used version 2 of the IATI Standard.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Provide data that adheres to the Standard’s Schema. The IATI Schema provides the exact order and format in which publishers provide their IATI files. Technical information about the IATI Schema can be found on <a href="http://reference.iatistandard.org/203/schema/">IATI’s Reference site</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Provide more fields for querying and searching IATI data.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>CALL TO ACTION: Please test the IATI Datastore Query Builder 08th October - 05th November)</strong></p>
<p>Users familiar with the IATI Standard are invited to test the new IATI Datastore Query Builder and provide feedback to the IATI Technical Team and <a href="https://www.zimmermanzimmerman.nl/">Zimmerman and Zimmerman</a>, which have worked closely together to develop this new tool. Specifically, users are invited to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Build queries and review the content of the data returned to ensure it accurately matches the elements/parameters selected</li>
<li>Check that the data returned is usable in its selected format (CSV, JSON, XML)</li>
<li>Report any issues</li>
</ul>
<p>Feedback should be provided by raising an issue with <a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/OIPA/issues">Github on the IATI Datastore</a> project. Users who are unable to access Github are welcome to share their feedback by emailing <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a>.</p>
<p>If after trying the tool users would like a demonstration of the Query Builder, they should send an email with specific questions to <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a> and if there is sufficient demand, the Technical Team will set up a webinar demonstration during the testing phase.</p>
<p><strong>What will happen after the new Datastore Query Builder testing phase?</strong></p>
<p>After the testing period ends on 5th November, the team will review all suggestions for changes that were not addressed during the testing phase to inform the next phase of work on the tool.</p>
<p>Based on the scope of changes needed following the testing phase, a date for the official launch of the Datastore Query Builder will be announced, and the old query builder will be phased out six months afterward.</p>
<p>Thanks in advance to IATI’s dedicated community who are able to support the testing phase of the IATI Datastore Query Builder. For any questions please email: <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a>.</p>
            <p><small>19 posts - 10 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-datastores-new-query-builder-is-launched-for-testing/1860">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-datastores-new-query-builder-is-launched-for-testing/1860</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 12:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1860</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/iati-datastores-new-query-builder-is-launched-for-testing/1860.rss">IATI Datastore&#39;s new Query Builder is launched for testing</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>New download publisher function on Registry</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi all,</p>
<p>The Tech Team is pleased to announce that we have implemented a ’Download List’ function on the <a href="https://iatiregistry.org/publisher" rel="nofollow noopener">Publisher List</a> page on the Registry.</p>
<p>The function allows users to instantly download the latest list of active publishers in CSV, XLS, XML or JSON formats.</p>
<p><strong>NOTE:</strong> If you are using the <a href="https://www.publishwhatyoufund.org/projects/iati-decipher/" rel="nofollow noopener">IATI Decipher</a> extension on Chrome or Firefox, the download button may not work correctly until your extension has been automatically updated to the latest version. See the <a href="https://github.com/pwyf/iati-decipher/issues/106" rel="nofollow noopener">GitHub issue</a> for details.</p>
            <p><small>5 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/new-download-publisher-function-on-registry/1854">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/new-download-publisher-function-on-registry/1854</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 11:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1854</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/new-download-publisher-function-on-registry/1854.rss">New download publisher function on Registry</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>New IATI Validator pre-launch update</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>IATI is set to launch its new online data validation tool during the autumn this year. The aim of the new IATI Validator (built by <a href="https://data4development.nl/en/" rel="nofollow noopener">Data4Development</a> and managed by IATI’s technical team) is to drive essential improvements in the quality of development and humanitarian data by checking that it complies with the rules and guidance of the IATI Standard.</p>
<h3><strong>Improving IATI validation</strong></h3>
<p>The new IATI Validator is being created to replace the existing <a href="http://validator.iatistandard.org/" rel="nofollow noopener">Public Validator</a>, to offer a more robust service. The new tool will check data against all rules in the IATI Standard; it is technically more robust and therefore easier to maintain, and will offer API endpoints so the service can be linked easily to other IATI tools.</p>
<h3><strong>Pre-launch Q&amp;A: New IATI Validator</strong></h3>
<p>Ahead of the launch, IATI’s technical team has published a <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1HVLJsAcerr9y9DfY1-P9ZckWTqoUgQWi9ix5xwFLeos/edit?usp=sharing" rel="nofollow noopener">Pre-launch Q&amp;A: New IATI Validator</a>. The document provides comprehensive information to IATI data publishers, users and developers about what to expect from the new IATI Validator. The Q&amp;A will be updated with additional questions from users together with responses, over the coming months.</p>
<h4><a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1HVLJsAcerr9y9DfY1-P9ZckWTqoUgQWi9ix5xwFLeos/edit?usp=sharing" rel="nofollow noopener">View Pre-launch Q&amp;A: New IATI Validator</a></h4>
<h3><strong>Increased IATI Standard checks</strong></h3>
<p>The new IATI Validator will check data against important rules of the IATI Standard that the existing <a href="http://validator.iatistandard.org/" rel="nofollow noopener">Public Validator</a> does not do. Therefore we anticipate that by using the new tool, many publishers will discover they have many corrections to make to their data, and these may take some time to deal with.</p>
<p>It is important to note that publishers are  <strong>not</strong>  expected to correct their data immediately and using the tool is just the first step in the process of improving IATI data quality. By making these changes, publishers can ensure their data is of the highest quality, and is accessible and reliable for anyone working with data on development and humanitarian resources and results.</p>
<h3><strong>Ahead of the launch…</strong></h3>
<p>Publishers are  <strong>not</strong>  expected to undertake lengthy reviews of their data to ensure it fully complies with the IATI Standard. Publishers are encouraged to wait for the IATI Validator to be launched and then start using the tool to automatically check their data quickly.</p>
<h3><strong>What support will be offered?</strong></h3>
<p>Once the new IATI Validator is launched, it will provide error and warning messages to the users about their files. Support will include:</p>
<ul>
<li>User documentation</li>
<li>IATI technical team helpdesk <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a>
</li>
<li>Upcoming webinars held by the IATI technical team on how to use the Validator</li>
<li>Peer-to-peer support through <a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/">IATI Discuss</a> (online community forum)</li>
<li>One-to-one calls with the technical team if required</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Further information</strong></h3>
<p>For full information about the launch of the new IATI Validator, please refer to the <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1HVLJsAcerr9y9DfY1-P9ZckWTqoUgQWi9ix5xwFLeos/edit?usp=sharing" rel="nofollow noopener">Pre-launch Q&amp;A: New IATI Validator</a>. Do email the IATI technical team at <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a> if you would like to request that the document is updated with additional questions and answers.</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/new-iati-validator-pre-launch-update/1822">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/new-iati-validator-pre-launch-update/1822</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 14:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1822</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/new-iati-validator-pre-launch-update/1822.rss">New IATI Validator pre-launch update</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>New IATI Datastore API launched for testing</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[IATI-techteam]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>IATI’s new Datastore API is being launched for a month of public testing between <strong>19 August and 18 September</strong>, as announced in the technical team’s <a href="https://iatistandard.org/en/news/iati-technical-team-quarterly-update/" rel="nofollow noopener">last quarterly update</a>.</p>
<p>IATI’s <a href="https://iatistandard.org/en/about/governance/who-runs-iati/technical-team/" rel="nofollow noopener">technical team</a> and <a href="https://www.zimmermanzimmerman.nl/" rel="nofollow noopener">Zimmerman and Zimmerman</a>, who are building the new Datastore, are calling on technical users to test the Datastore API and provide feedback.</p>
<p><strong>Try new <a href="https://test-datastore.iatistandard.org/api/" rel="nofollow noopener">Datastore API</a> now. See <a href="https://docs.oipa.nl/?version=latest" rel="nofollow noopener">documentation</a> on how to use the API.</strong></p>
<p><strong>About the new Datastore</strong></p>
<p>The new IATI Datastore aims to offer a robust online data service, providing timely and standardised access to data published according to the IATI Standard. Initially, users can gain data on development and humanitarian resources and results through using the <a href="https://test-datastore.iatistandard.org/api/" rel="nofollow noopener">Datastore’s API</a>. Users will also be able to download data from a new user-friendly Datastore Query Builder, which is due to be released shortly for testing.</p>
<p><strong>What data can be accessed?</strong></p>
<p>The new <a href="https://test-datastore.iatistandard.org/api/" rel="nofollow noopener">IATI Datastore API</a> provides data published by organisations who have used version 2 of the IATI Standard. This is following the decision to deprecate <a href="https://iatistandard.org/en/news/notice-iati-standard-version-1-is-deprecated/" rel="nofollow noopener">version 1 by IATI members</a>, which was implemented last month.</p>
<p>To help users access good quality data, the Datastore will not hold any data that does not adhere to the IATI Schema. The IATI Schema provides the exact order and format that publishers should provide their XML files in. More information about the Schema can be found on <a href="http://reference.iatistandard.org/203/schema/" rel="nofollow noopener">IATI’s Reference site</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Testing the new Datastore API (19 Aug - 18 Sept)</strong></p>
<p>Users are invited to <a href="https://test-datastore.iatistandard.org/api/" rel="nofollow noopener">test the API</a> to build queries of selected IATI data and review the output of data from the Datastore. Specifically users are requested to:</p>
<ul>
<li>check that they can filter the data by the elements/parameters they require;</li>
<li>review the content of the data that is returned to ensure it accurately matches the elements/parameters selected and,</li>
<li>check that the output they receive is usable and matches their expectations.</li>
</ul>
<p>When testing, please refer to the <a href="https://docs.oipa.nl/?version=latest" rel="nofollow noopener">Datastore API documentation</a> and <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1nTu1Jdg17toiQoemJT3R9YPwvAwCN1gpFnnL1R-lfHY/edit?usp=sharing" rel="nofollow noopener">IATI Datastore – API mapping and examples</a>, then provide your feedback on Github on the <a href="https://github.com/zimmerman-zimmerman/OIPA/projects/5" rel="nofollow noopener">IATI Datastore project</a>. This will help the technical team and Zimmerman and Zimmerman more easily review feedback and, where applicable, convert issues directly into GitHub tickets to work on.</p>
<p><strong>What will happen after the Datastore testing phase?</strong></p>
<p>After the testing deadline of 18 September, the technical team and Zimmerman and Zimmerman will post an update about the collected feedback on IATI Discuss. They will also contact users individually if more information is needed, continue triaging issues and action changes where required.</p>
<p>Based on the scope of the testing phase and its follow-up weeks, a date for the official launch of the Datastore will be set and the old Datastore will be phased out 6 months after this date.</p>
<p><strong>Help to transition from using the old datastore to the new IATI Datastore</strong></p>
<p>The technical team will be working to ensure that users can smoothly transition from using the old datastore to using the new IATI Datastore. They will:</p>
<ul>
<li>provide a <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1nTu1Jdg17toiQoemJT3R9YPwvAwCN1gpFnnL1R-lfHY/edit?usp=sharing" rel="nofollow noopener">mapping document with some examples</a> to help testing and migrating between Datastore versions</li>
<li>provide automated redirects from old to new datastore API calls for 6 months</li>
<li>publish API documentation and a User Manual</li>
<li>offer direct support from the technical team via email or one-to-one calls.</li>
</ul>
<p>Thanks in advance to IATI’s dedicated community who are able to support the testing phase of the Datastore. The technical team and Zimmerman and Zimmerman look forward to receiving your feedback. For any questions please email: <a href="mailto:support@iatistandard.org">support@iatistandard.org</a>.</p>
            <p><small>7 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/new-iati-datastore-api-launched-for-testing/1815">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/new-iati-datastore-api-launched-for-testing/1815</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 13:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1815</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/new-iati-datastore-api-launched-for-testing/1815.rss">New IATI Datastore API launched for testing</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Dashboard and Publishing Statistics Split</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[WendyThomas]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Following a decision at last year’s Technical Audit, our developers have been working on moving the IATI Publishing Statistics section from <a href="http://dashboard.iatistandard.org/" rel="nofollow noopener">dashboard.iatistandard.org/</a> onto a separate website, in order to better meet the different needs of internal and external users of the tool and to improve the tool’s performance. Developer John Askew has now completed a big piece of work to split the code, enabling us to launch the Dashboard and Publishing Statistics as two separate platforms:</p>
<ul>
<li>The <a href="http://dashboard.iatistandard.org" rel="nofollow noopener">IATI-Dashboard</a>
</li>
<li>The new <a href="http://publishingstats.iatistandard.org" rel="nofollow noopener">Publishing Statistics</a> portal</li>
</ul>
<p>For our Users, the viewing and browsing experience will not change: we have updated all the links to now point to either portal’s pages and we have also provided a redirect system that will automatically redirect your existing bookmarks to the new Publishing Statistics url’s version of the pages.</p>
<p>A big benefit of this work is improved and updated performance: now both tools can aggregate, crunch and rebuild the pages on a daily basis. (Previously the dashboard did not update daily.) It will also make it easier for the Tech Team to investigate and debug anything that does not function properly.</p>
<p>The code for Publishing Statistics is hosted at <a href="https://github.com/IATI/IATI-Publishing-Statistics" rel="nofollow noopener">https://github.com/IATI/IATI-Publishing-Statistics</a> while the Dashboard is still at its old home <a href="https://github.com/IATI/IATI-Dashboard" rel="nofollow noopener">https://github.com/IATI/IATI-Dashboard</a></p>
<p>Thanks John for all your work on this!</p>
<p>Wendy Thomas, IATI Technical Lead</p>
            <p><small>5 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/dashboard-and-publishing-statistics-split/1811">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/dashboard-and-publishing-statistics-split/1811</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 15:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1811</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/dashboard-and-publishing-statistics-split/1811.rss">Dashboard and Publishing Statistics Split</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Community guidelines - update</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[aparr]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Notifications</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Dear All</p>
<p>We’ve had good cause over this past month to celebrate IATI’s incredible milestone of 1000 publishers, thanks in large part to our fantastic Tech Team (never quite celebrated enough). I’m also thankful for a committed community that enthusiastically contributes time and expertise in support of the team’s work. With growth however comes challenge, and I’m reaching out to the community now to seek all of your support in meeting the current challenge.</p>
<p>In order to address some of the technical debt that has resulted from IATI’s rapid growth, the Governing Board worked with community experts on a <a href="https://iatistandard.org/en/news/board-decisions-on-iati-technical-audit/" rel="nofollow noopener">technical audit</a> last autumn, and based on the recommendations of the audit, the Board set out an ambitious workplan for the Tech Team for the remainder of the 2018/19 period. Over the coming months you’ll see the results including the new datastore and a new validator; the dashboard is also undergoing some essential improvements, as is the website. These and other planned activities are all coming together thanks to our tech team working with external service providers.</p>
<p>As Secretariat Coordinator I’m keen to make sure we continue to make the progress IATI needs to see according to the timeframe agreed with the Board. We have a clear workplan and accountability structure through the Board with which to achieve it, and major deliverables between now and the Members’ Assembly in September. With the departure last week of one of our key developers however, with pressure from the community cited as a factor in the decision to leave, our team’s capacity is reduced, putting progress in key activities at risk.</p>
<p>Having consulted with the Board, I’m sharing these clarifications on roles, responsibilities and processes to ensure that the team has the resources and space they need to do their work, and that they can do so in a supportive environment. This approach is proposed as an interim measure while we work with the community to establish robust processes for the longer term.</p>
<p>I am requesting the commitment of both tech team and community members to follow these processes which I believe will allow the Secretariat to deliver what the Board and members expect, whilst ensuring that community members continue to play their important roles.</p>
<p><strong>Clarification of roles and responsibilities</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>The Governing Board provides strategic guidance on all technical decisions. Formal announcements regarding Board decisions on technical issues will be communicated via the IATI website and the TAG newsletter.</li>
<li>The TAG Chair is the liaison between the community and the Board. It is his role to represent the Board, convey and explain formal Board decisions to the community, and raise issues from the community to the Board. The TAG Chair works with a second Board technical focal point and maintains regular contact with the Technical Lead.</li>
<li>The Technical Lead manages the Tech Team and is responsible to the Board for the implementation of the technical workplan.</li>
<li>The Tech Team is responsible for delivering the activities in the technical workplan. With the Technical Lead, the Tech Team will continue to meet with Board technical focal points on a quarterly basis and publish updates on their progress and plans after each quarterly meeting.</li>
<li>The TAG Community is encouraged to share best practices and suggestions or solutions to problems through the Discuss forum and technical code through Github.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Issues, suggestions and escalation procedures</strong></p>
<ol start="6">
<li>The Technical Team will prioritise activities and discussions that assist in delivering on agreed quarterly workplan commitments, drawing on the experience of the community particularly where it comes to technical code reviews.</li>
<li>Key issues that may result in deviation from the approved workplan will be brought to the attention of the Technical Lead who in turn will escalate to the Coordinator, TAG Chair and/or relevant Board focal points for appropriate response or action.</li>
</ol>
<p>As part of our review of the future of the TAG, we will also work together with the community to develop a more formal code of conduct and the processes that will help to guide our interactions and improve our accountability. This will however take some time and will need the input of the Secretariat working together with the community to ensure that everybody’s needs and expectations are properly met.</p>
<p>I want to reiterate the enormous appreciation we have for the support received each day from the community. Above all, however, I want to ensure that our staff can work in a safe, respectful and supportive environment which enables each of us to do what we are mandated to do; I’m seeking all of your support to ensure we can achieve the results we need to see.</p>
<p>Thanks very much,</p>
<p>Annelise<br>
IATI Secretariat Coordinator</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/community-guidelines-update/1769">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/community-guidelines-update/1769</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 21:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-1769</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/community-guidelines-update/1769.rss">Community guidelines - update</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
