<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>IATI TAG 2015 - IATI Community Discussions</title>
    <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/c/events/iati-tag-2015/19</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;IATI TAG 2015&#39; category The &lt;strong&gt;IATI TAG&lt;/strong&gt; will be held in May 2015. </description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 15:20:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/c/events/iati-tag-2015/19.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>Priorities for the TAG community in 2015-16</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[JoniHillman]]></dc:creator>
          <category>IATI TAG 2015</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Following the many and varied discussions in Ottawa, the emerging key priorities for the IATI community over the coming year seem to be:</p>
<ul>
<li>Stimulating and supporting <strong>demand for and use of IATI data</strong>, particularly in developing countries</li>
<li>
<strong>Enhancing the IATI Standard</strong> by adding a Humanitarian extension and further developing the Results element</li>
<li>Fulfilling the ‘<strong>publish once, use often</strong>’ approach - trialling using IATI data for donor reports to the CRS and NGO reporting to donors</li>
</ul>
<p>Do you agree? Would you like to get involved / lead on some of this work? Tell us!</p>
            <p><small>4 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/priorities-for-the-tag-community-in-2015-16/301">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/priorities-for-the-tag-community-in-2015-16/301</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 15:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-301</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/priorities-for-the-tag-community-in-2015-16/301.rss">Priorities for the TAG community in 2015-16</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Report on TAG 2015?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[MichaelMedley]]></dc:creator>
          <category>IATI TAG 2015</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Will there be a report on the outcomes of TAG 2015? Come to that, are reports available of previous TAG meetings?</p>
            <p><small>3 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/report-on-tag-2015/284">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/report-on-tag-2015/284</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-284</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/report-on-tag-2015/284.rss">Report on TAG 2015?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>TAG 2015 Agenda is now live!</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[JoniHillman]]></dc:creator>
          <category>IATI TAG 2015</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The agenda is now live at <a href="http://www.aidtransparency.net/technicaladvisorygroup/tag-meetings/tag-meeting-may-2015/tag-2015-agenda">http://www.aidtransparency.net/technicaladvisorygroup/tag-meetings/tag-meeting-may-2015/tag-2015-agenda</a></p>
<p>We’re using Sched again so please either set up an account or revive your log in from last year and register for the sessions you want to attend.</p>
<p>We’ll be adding in more detail about each session over the next day or two but the timings are all set now.</p>
<p>Looking forward to seeing you all in Ottawa!</p>
<p>Joni</p>
            <p><small>1 post - 1 participant</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/tag-2015-agenda-is-now-live/196">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/tag-2015-agenda-is-now-live/196</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 21:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-196</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/tag-2015-agenda-is-now-live/196.rss">TAG 2015 Agenda is now live!</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>State of IATI 2015</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[JohnAdams]]></dc:creator>
          <category>IATI TAG 2015</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I plan to open the first plenary on Saturday 30 May with a short summary of where I think we are as a standard and as a technical community.</p>
<p>This year the TAG has three broad themes:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>Getting it Right:</strong> how do we make sure that we’re publishing the most useful and best quality data we can?</li>
<li>
<strong>Using the Data:</strong> how do we make it easy for people to use the data?</li>
<li>
<strong>What Next?</strong> what is next for the IATI standard and community?</li>
</ul>
<p>In the talk, I’d like to reflect views from people across the IATI TAG community. I’d like us to go into the main part of the TAG with an acknowledgement of how far we have come in establishing a robust international data standard, but also recognising the challenges that we will face in 2015 and beyond.</p>
<p>So I’d like your help in answering the following three questions:</p>
<p><strong>1. What have our key successes been in the last 18 months or so? What have we as a community done particularly well? What should we celebrate?</strong><br>
<strong>2. Where could we have done better?</strong><br>
<strong>3. What are the key challenges we face in 2015, as we lead up to the Busan deadline? And what can we do about those challenges?</strong></p>
<p>I appreciate those are big questions, but help me out here! Any responses this week will let me process my thoughts as I travel to Ottawa.</p>
<p>I look forward to seeing as many of you as possible in Ottawa at the end of next week!</p>
<p>John</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/state-of-iati-2015/195">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/state-of-iati-2015/195</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 19:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-195</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/state-of-iati-2015/195.rss">State of IATI 2015</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>CSO and NGO side session at TAG: good idea?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[SJohns]]></dc:creator>
          <category>IATI TAG 2015</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello, we’re thinking about having a side event at the TAG, probably on Saturday morning, for CSOs, NGOs and NGO platforms involved in IATI so that we can meet each other and have a chat before the TAG and Steering Committee meetings kick off. If you think this is a good idea, please let us know by replying to this thread. Thanks! Sarah (on behalf of the CSO Working Group).</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/cso-and-ngo-side-session-at-tag-good-idea/179">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/cso-and-ngo-side-session-at-tag-good-idea/179</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 14:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-179</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/cso-and-ngo-side-session-at-tag-good-idea/179.rss">CSO and NGO side session at TAG: good idea?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Here&#39;s the draft agenda! Tell us what you think</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[JoniHillman]]></dc:creator>
          <category>IATI TAG 2015</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thank you to everyone who has contributed ideas on Discuss, there certainly has been some vibrant discussion. We want to make sure the agenda we present really meets the needs of the community so we’ve noted the suggestions that were made and now want to come back to you all to check we’ve got it right.</p>
<p>We’ve developed a draft agenda which you can see in a <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/14K2thOiWGjuWJM5_IfMgWTxUS5TOjjbJJ_UsWPSL70U/edit?usp=sharing">Google Doc</a>. We are looking for your feedback on the following specific areas:</p>
<ul>
<li>Are there any <strong>key topics missing</strong> from the agenda?</li>
<li>Would you be willing to <strong>volunteer to facilitate a specific session</strong> that you’re<br>
most interested in?</li>
<li>Which <strong>sessions could you contribute to</strong> in an active way (by speaking, co-ordinating, presenting some ideas etc)?</li>
<li>Would you like to give a <strong>lightening talk</strong> (max. 5 minutes) on something you’re working on that relates to one of the three agenda themes (Getting it right; Using the data; What next)?</li>
</ul>
<p>Please let us know by commenting in the <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/14K2thOiWGjuWJM5_IfMgWTxUS5TOjjbJJ_UsWPSL70U/edit?usp=sharing">Google Doc</a> or commenting on this thread <strong>by Friday 8 May</strong>.</p>
            <p><small>13 posts - 5 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/heres-the-draft-agenda-tell-us-what-you-think/175">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/heres-the-draft-agenda-tell-us-what-you-think/175</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 14:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-175</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/heres-the-draft-agenda-tell-us-what-you-think/175.rss">Here&#39;s the draft agenda! Tell us what you think</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Nepal Earthquake: tagging IATI data</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[SJohns]]></dc:creator>
          <category>IATI TAG 2015</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello, it would be good to talk humanitarian at the TAG - is there going to be a session? In particular, how to tag data as relating to a particular emergency response (I’m thinking Nepal earthquake here) and record funding and results at the end of the 90 day response period. (Not thinking of IATI as coordination mechanism as there are other better things for that). Has anyone got  prior experience of this? I know that there were conversations on here last year, but nothing resolved.</p>
            <p><small>7 posts - 4 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/nepal-earthquake-tagging-iati-data/174">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/nepal-earthquake-tagging-iati-data/174</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 09:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-174</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/nepal-earthquake-tagging-iati-data/174.rss">Nepal Earthquake: tagging IATI data</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Activity results (and objectives)</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[MichaelMedley]]></dc:creator>
          <category>IATI TAG 2015</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Continuing the discussion from <a href="//discuss.iatistandard.org/t/bright-ideas-for-the-tag/134/11">Bright ideas for the TAG</a>:</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-post="11" data-topic="134">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="//discuss.iatistandard.org/user_avatar/discuss.iatistandard.org/herb_caudill/40/51_1.png" class="avatar"><a href="//discuss.iatistandard.org/t/bright-ideas-for-the-tag/134/11">Bright ideas for the TAG</a>
</div>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!topic/iati-technical/IlU05TlGjHE" rel="nofollow noopener">https://groups.google.com/forum/#!topic/iati-technical/IlU05TlGjHE</a></p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I agree it is extremely important that aid agencies report their activity results, and that everyone can access these reports through IATI. I am in awe of the analytical grasp that Herb_Caudill has brought to bear on this. But it seems over-ambitious in the forseeable future to think in terms of a way in which indicators can be rigorously defined machine-readably for all activities.</p>
<p>A key point is that different activities - and within those, different objectives - are differently amenable to standardization. It may not be too difficult to count the number of children to whom your project has helped give a basic education, and it is certainly useful to be able to aggregate that number with others in local and national statistics. But not all objectives are like that.</p>
<p>Let’s say your objective is to build an all-weather road from Amule to Buba. A simple way of reporting the achievement of that objective in an aggregatable way is to say you built 100km of road. But the validity of any aggregation along those lines will be dubious because a road from Amule to Buba is a unique matter, entirely different in character from a road between Calakal and Dor. Measuring things like volume of traffic or value of merchandise does not absolve you from that because any assessment of the impact of the project has to take into account a host of other costs and benefits. Unless you follow the path of calculating everything into a single number using a full social cost-benefit analysis, you are left with a hopeless number of interpretable dimensions. Social cost-benefit analysis is less popular than it once was, and for good reason. In reality it hides many doubtful and politically controversial questions behind a facade of economic expertise.</p>
<p>Or take another example: one which you use in your exposition, Herb: training journalists. What matters in the result is not merely the number of journalists trained, and how they may be disaggregated by gender, ethnic group and so on. It is important to know how thorough the training was (a day or a year? Full-time or part-time etc), and about the features of the curriculum being used. It would be extremely complex and difficult to resolve these matters into machine-readable indicators, and the effort to do so would have unwanted side-effects. Not only would it increase the number of headaches in the publishing agency and deter it from using IATI at all; it might even end up forcing them to design their projects to fit in with the standardized indicators (including packages of standardized curricula) on offer. (I know you will say they can define their own indicators, Herb, but suspect they might feel it easier - or be pressurized - to take indicators off the peg.)</p>
<p>In the end, why do we want to aggregate results? Mainly for purposes of centralized planning and policy discussions. In some cases (like the provision of basic education) it is quite legitimate. In others - like roads - the planners and policy-makers really should not be shielding themselves from the social and political complexities behind pseudo-objective numbers. And in others again - like training journalists - it may be better not to involve central planners at all.</p>
<p>So what would my recommendations be for the TAG?</p>
<p>Remember that the essence of IATI is not necessarily to provide aggregatable or machine-analyzable data. The more fundamental purpose is to provide accessible information. For citizens, this may mean being able to find, understand, and follow up on the individual activities which are going to impact them, or which have impacted them, or which their government has funded or allowed to happen in their country.</p>
<p>There may be a case for providing some facility for using standardized indicators, but this should not be seen as something generalizable to every reported activity.</p>
<p>Being new to this space, I do not understand how the IATI standard has come to support a family of tags called “result” rather than “objective”. The IATI standard was supposed to be forward-looking (presumably in contrast to the OECD CRS). “Result” seems very backward-looking. Citizens and recipient-country governments need an easier way of knowing what aid agencies are planning to do and what they are in the middle of doing. Recording obejctives at the beginning also strengthens post-hoc accountability by allowing clear comparison of promises with, well, claimed results.</p>
<p>I do not think it should be stipulated that a “result” (or an “objective”) needs to be measurable. This job is done by indicators.</p>
<p>Apart from allowing and encouraging the reporting of pre-completion objectives, do not make the standard more complex. The priority should be to make donors and other publishers actually use those tag fields for reporting objectives, results and - above all - links to useful documents.</p>
            <p><small>19 posts - 3 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/activity-results-and-objectives/172">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/activity-results-and-objectives/172</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 08:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-172</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/activity-results-and-objectives/172.rss">Activity results (and objectives)</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Bright ideas for the TAG</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[JohnAdams]]></dc:creator>
          <category>IATI TAG 2015</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>How do we make the TAG an exciting forum for the exchange of ideas? What have you seen that works well in other conferences that we could copy and adapt?</p>
            <p><small>13 posts - 9 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/bright-ideas-for-the-tag/134">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/bright-ideas-for-the-tag/134</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 14:18:10 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-134</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/bright-ideas-for-the-tag/134.rss">Bright ideas for the TAG</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>What Next? Theme</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[JohnAdams]]></dc:creator>
          <category>IATI TAG 2015</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The major milestone of early 2015 was the move to IATI 2.01. So what comes next? Is it closer integration with other open data initiatives (HDX, EITI, OpenContracting)? Is it soemthing else? Where can we continually improve?</p>
            <p><small>8 posts - 7 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/what-next-theme/133">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/what-next-theme/133</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 14:17:10 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-133</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/what-next-theme/133.rss">What Next? Theme</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Using the Data Theme</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[JohnAdams]]></dc:creator>
          <category>IATI TAG 2015</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>There’s no point in publishers putting lots of effort into IATI if no-one uses the data. So how do we make it easy for people to use the data? Are there tools and techniques that make IATI data easier to use by different groups of people? Are there ways the IATI community can help?</p>
            <p><small>33 posts - 15 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/using-the-data-theme/132">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/using-the-data-theme/132</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 14:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-132</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/using-the-data-theme/132.rss">Using the Data Theme</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Getting it Right Theme</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[JohnAdams]]></dc:creator>
          <category>IATI TAG 2015</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Getting it Right is about helping publishers to publish for the first time. Or about helping publishers to improve the quality of their data. Or about getting better at the GPEDC or Aid Transparency Indexes! What would you like to see under this theme?</p>
            <p><small>10 posts - 6 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/getting-it-right-theme/131">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/getting-it-right-theme/131</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 14:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-131</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/getting-it-right-theme/131.rss">Getting it Right Theme</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>About the IATI TAG 2015 category</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adrian]]></dc:creator>
          <category>IATI TAG 2015</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The <strong>IATI TAG</strong> will be held in May 2015.</p>
<p>As previously, the three main themes of the TAG this year will be:</p>
<p>•	<strong>Getting it Right</strong> – from first time publishers to those wanting to continually improve the quality of their data<br>
•	<strong>Using the Data</strong> – how do we encourage and make it easy for people to use the wealth of IATI data?<br>
•	<strong>What Next?</strong> – how do we evolve the standard and link up with other initiatives?</p>
<p>We want to use this discussion forum to begin thinking about the types of topics we want to include under those themes.</p>
<p>But also to reflect on how we could run the TAG meeting – so we’d be interested to know what works well, what could we improve on, are there any innovative ideas from elsewhere that we could copy?</p>
<p>Get discussing!</p>
            <p><small>2 posts - 2 participants</small></p>
            <p><a href="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/about-the-iati-tag-2015-category/121">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/about-the-iati-tag-2015-category/121</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 09:18:10 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>Yes</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.iatistandard.org-topic-121</guid>
          <source url="https://discuss.iatistandard.org/t/about-the-iati-tag-2015-category/121.rss">About the IATI TAG 2015 category</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
